<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AG Ahrens Publikationen (IAU)</title>
    <link>https://www.iau.uni-frankfurt.de</link>
    <description>Publikationen der AG Ahrens, Institut für Atmosphäre und Umwelt (IAU)</description>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Zotero Feed Generator Script (AG Ahrens)</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://184467gianluca.github.io/institut-zotero-feed/AG_Ahrens_zotero_rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parras-Berrocal, I. M.; Waldman, R.; Sevault, F.; Somot, S.; Gonzalez, N.; Ahrens, B.; Anav, A.; Djurdjević, V.; Gualdi, S.; Hamouda, M. E.; Li, L.; Lionello, P.; Sannino, G.; Sein, D. V. (2024) Response of the Mediterranean Sea Surface Circulation at Various Global Warming Levels: A Multi-Model Approach. Geophysical Research Letters. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024GL111695</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6BMMCUXJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaertner, Miguel Ángel; González-Alemán, Juan Jesús; Romera, Raquel; Domínguez, Marta; Gil, Victoria; Sánchez, Enrique; Gallardo, Clemente; Miglietta, Mario Marcello; Walsh, Kevin J. E.; Sein, Dmitry V.; Somot, Samuel; Dell’Aquila, Alessandro; Teichmann, Claas; Ahrens, Bodo; Buonomo, Erasmo; Colette, Augustin; Bastin, Sophie; van Meijgaard, Erik; Nikulin, Grigory (2018) Simulation of medicanes over the Mediterranean Sea in a regional climate model ensemble: impact of ocean–atmosphere coupling and increased resolution. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3456-1</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HR2BKUGP</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fantini, Adriano; Raffaele, Francesca; Torma, Csaba; Bacer, Sara; Coppola, Erika; Giorgi, Filippo; Ahrens, Bodo; Dubois, Clotilde; Sanchez, Enrique; Verdecchia, Marco (2018) Assessment of multiple daily precipitation statistics in ERA-Interim driven Med-CORDEX and EURO-CORDEX experiments against high resolution observations. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3453-4</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YGLWWMVS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cavicchia, Leone; Scoccimarro, Enrico; Gualdi, Silvio; Marson, Paola; Ahrens, Bodo; Berthou, Ségolène; Conte, Dario; Dell’Aquila, Alessandro; Drobinski, Philippe; Djurdjevic, Vladimir; Dubois, Clotilde; Gallardo, Clemente; Li, Laurent; Oddo, Paolo; Sanna, Antonella; Torma, Csaba (2018) Mediterranean extreme precipitation: a multi-model assessment. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3245-x</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PF43N8N8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drobinski, Philippe; Silva, Nicolas Da; Panthou, Gérémy; Bastin, Sophie; Muller, Caroline; Ahrens, Bodo; Borga, Marco; Conte, Dario; Fosser, Giorgia; Giorgi, Filippo; Güttler, Ivan; Kotroni, Vassiliki; Li, Laurent; Morin, Efrat; Önol, Bariş; Quintana-Segui, Pere; Romera, Raquel; Torma, Csaba Zsolt (2018) Scaling precipitation extremes with temperature in the Mediterranean: past climate assessment and projection in anthropogenic scenarios. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3083-x</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">CJB6XSFU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obermann, Anika; Bastin, Sophie; Belamari, Sophie; Conte, Dario; Gaertner, Miguel Angel; Li, Laurent; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) Mistral and Tramontane wind speed and wind direction patterns in regional climate simulations. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3053-3</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LAVPCXDZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Osuri, Krishna K.; Pattanayak, Sujata; Mohanty, U. C.; Sil, Sourav; Nadimpalli, Raghu (2017) Observational perspective of SST changes during life cycle of tropical cyclones over Bay of Bengal. Natural Hazards. 88</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11069-017-2945-9</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VH9M4N82</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirchgessner, Paul; Tödter, Julian; Ahrens, Bodo; Nerger, Lars (2017) The smoother extension of the nonlinear ensemble transform filter. Tellus A: Dynamic Meteorology and Oceanography. 69</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/16000870.2017.1327766</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HELCC8BN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paeth, Heiko; Paxian, Andreas; Sein, Dmitry V.; Jacob, Daniela; Panitz, Hans-Jürgen; Warscher, Michael; Fink, Andreas H.; Kunstmann, Harald; Breil, Marcus; Engel, Thomas; Krause, Andreas; Toedter, Julian; Ahrens, Bodo (2017) Decadal and multi-year predictability of the West African monsoon and the role of dynamical downscaling. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2017/0811</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UT5HJ8XI</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flaounas, Emmanouil; Kelemen, Fanni Dora; Wernli, Heini; Gaertner, Miguel Angel; Reale, Marco; Sanchez-Gomez, Emilia; Lionello, Piero; Calmanti, Sandro; Podrascanin, Zorica; Somot, Samuel; Akhtar, Naveed; Romera, Raquel; Conte, Dario (2018) Assessment of an ensemble of ocean–atmosphere coupled and uncoupled regional climate models to reproduce the climatology of Mediterranean cyclones. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3398-7</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UPN7S7P7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will, Andreas; Akhtar, Naveed; Brauch, Jennifer; Breil, Marcus; Davin, Edouard; Ho-Hagemann, Ha T. M.; Maisonnave, Eric; Thürkow, Markus; Weiher, Stefan (2017) The COSMO-CLM 4.8 regional climate model coupled to regional ocean, land surface and global earth system models using OASIS3-MCT: description and performance. Geoscientific Model Development. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-10-1549-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8LC268ZL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harzallah, Ali; Jordà, Gabriel; Dubois, Clotilde; Sannino, Gianmaria; Carillo, Adriana; Li, Laurent; Arsouze, Thomas; Cavicchia, Leone; Beuvier, Jonathan; Akhtar, Naveed (2018) Long term evolution of heat budget in the Mediterranean Sea from Med-CORDEX forced and coupled simulations. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3363-5</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DDZKSQ9S</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pham, Trang Van; Brauch, Jennifer; Früh, Barbara; Ahrens, Bodo (2017) Simulation of snowbands in the Baltic Sea area with the coupled atmosphere-ocean-ice model COSMO-CLM/NEMO. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2016/0775</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YWC8ANA9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brisson, Erwan; Van Weverberg, Kwinten; Demuzere, Matthias; Devis, Annemarie; Saeed, Sajjad; Stengel, Martin; van Lipzig, Nicole P. M. (2016) How well can a convection-permitting climate model reproduce decadal statistics of precipitation, temperature and cloud characteristics?. Climate Dynamics. 47</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3012-z</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">X8FNLLF8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Müller Schmied, Hannes; Müller, Richard; Sanchez-Lorenzo, Arturo; Ahrens, Bodo; Wild, Martin (2016) Evaluation of Radiation Components in a Global Freshwater Model with Station-Based Observations. Water. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w8100450</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KDWQBNCN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Llasses, J.; Jordà, G.; Gomis, D.; Adloff, F.; Macías, D.; Harzallah, A.; Arsouze, T.; Akthar, N.; Li, L.; Elizalde, A.; Sannino, G. (2018) Heat and salt redistribution within the Mediterranean Sea in the Med-CORDEX model ensemble. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-016-3242-0</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EYSIHHJN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obermann, Anika; Edelmann, Benedikt; Ahrens, Bodo (2016) Influence of sea surface roughness length parameterization on Mistral and Tramontane simulations. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/asr-13-107-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4BPTJKEK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schulz, Jan-Peter; Vogel, Gerd; Becker, Claudia; Kothe, Steffen; Rummel, Udo; Ahrens, Bodo (2016) Evaluation of the ground heat flux simulated by a multi-layer land surface scheme using high-quality observations at grass land and bare soil. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2016/0537</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6564D929</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paxian, A.; Sein, D.; Panitz, H.-J.; Warscher, M.; Breil, M.; Engel, T.; Tödter, J.; Krause, A.; Cabos Narvaez, W. D.; Fink, A. H.; Ahrens, B.; Kunstmann, H.; Jacob, D.; Paeth, H. (2016) Bias reduction in decadal predictions of West African monsoon rainfall using regional climate models. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 121</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2015JD024143</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5U342M6W</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kothe, Steffen; Tödter, Julian; Ahrens, Bodo (2016) Strategies for soil initialization of regional decadal climate predictions. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2016/0729</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NJ4MYFN2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruti, P. M.; Somot, S.; Giorgi, F.; Dubois, C.; Flaounas, E.; Obermann, A.; Dell’Aquila, A.; Pisacane, G.; Harzallah, A.; Lombardi, E.; Ahrens, B.; Akhtar, N.; Alias, A.; Arsouze, T.; Aznar, R.; Bastin, S.; Bartholy, J.; Béranger, K.; Beuvier, J.; Bouffies-Cloché, S.; Brauch, J.; Cabos, W.; Calmanti, S.; Calvet, J.-C.; Carillo, A.; Conte, D.; Coppola, E.; Djurdjevic, V.; Drobinski, P.; Elizalde-Arellano, A.; Gaertner, M.; Galàn, P.; Gallardo, C.; Gualdi, S.; Goncalves, M.; Jorba, O.; Jordà, G.; L’Heveder, B.; Lebeaupin-Brossier, C.; Li, L.; Liguori, G.; Lionello, P.; Maciàs, D.; Nabat, P.; Önol, B.; Raikovic, B.; Ramage, K.; Sevault, F.; Sannino, G.; Struglia, M. V.; Sanna, A.; Torma, C.; Vervatis, V. (2016) Med-CORDEX Initiative for Mediterranean Climate Studies. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. 97</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-14-00176.1</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">553JUGM2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Junghänel, Thomas; Brendel, Christoph; Winterrath, Tanja; Walter, Andreas (2016) Towards a radar- and observation-based hail climatology for Germany. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2016/0734</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ES8XKYBC</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brisson, Erwan; Demuzere, Matthias; Van Lipzig, Nicole P.M. (2016) Modelling strategies for performing convection-permitting climate simulations. Meteorologische Zeitschrift. 25</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2015/0598</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GZ24AI2T</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of a Nonlinear Ensemble Transform Filter for High-Dimensional Data Assimilation in: Monthly Weather Review Volume 144 Issue 1 (2016)</title>
      <link>https://journals.ametsoc.org/view/journals/mwre/144/1/mwr-d-15-0073.1.xml</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HXSFI9DK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tödter, Julian; Kirchgessner, Paul; Nerger, Lars; Ahrens, Bodo (2016) Assessment of a Nonlinear Ensemble Transform Filter for High-Dimensional Data Assimilation. Monthly Weather Review. 144</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-15-0073.1</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">S3SV83UE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molina, A.; Vanacker, V.; Brisson, E.; Mora, D.; Balthazar, V. (2015) Multidecadal change in streamflow associated with anthropogenic disturbances in the tropical Andes. Hydrology and Earth System Sciences. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/hess-19-4201-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SWLAAFIF</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prein, Andreas F.; Langhans, Wolfgang; Fosser, Giorgia; Ferrone, Andrew; Ban, Nikolina; Goergen, Klaus; Keller, Michael; Tölle, Merja; Gutjahr, Oliver; Feser, Frauke; Brisson, Erwan; Kollet, Stefan; Schmidli, Juerg; van Lipzig, Nicole P. M.; Leung, Ruby (2015) A review on regional convection-permitting climate modeling: Demonstrations, prospects, and challenges. Reviews of Geophysics. 53</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2014RG000475</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4AKD6C95</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pfeifroth, Uwe; Trentmann, Jörg; Fink, Andreas H.; Ahrens, Bodo (2016) Evaluating Satellite-Based Diurnal Cycles of Precipitation in the African Tropics. Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology. 55</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-15-0065.1</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VPNHB82K</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warwade, Pratibha; Sharma, Nayan; Ahrens, Bodo; Pandey, Ashish (2015) CHARACTERIZATION AND ANALYSIS OF THE TREND OF CLIMATE VARIABLE (TEMPERATURES) FOR THE NORTH EASTERN REGION OF THE INDIA. 6</title>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TYMVE5M5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhimal, Meghnath; Ahrens, Bodo; Kuch, Ulrich (2015) Climate Change and Spatiotemporal Distributions of Vector-Borne Diseases in Nepal – A Systematic Synthesis of Literature. PLOS ONE. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0129869</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5RIRV4JV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asharaf, Shakeel; Ahrens, Bodo (2015) Indian Summer Monsoon Rainfall Processes in Climate Change Scenarios. Journal of Climate. 28</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-14-00233.1</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3XCHAKYK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhimal, Meghnath; Gautam, Ishan; Joshi, Hari Datt; O’Hara, Robert B.; Ahrens, Bodo; Kuch, Ulrich (2015) Risk Factors for the Presence of Chikungunya and Dengue Vectors (Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus), Their Altitudinal Distribution and Climatic Determinants of Their Abundance in Central Nepal. PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases. 9</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0003545</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HLJICDPQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Second-Order Exact Ensemble Square Root Filter for Nonlinear Data Assimilation in: Monthly Weather Review Volume 143 Issue 4 (2015)</title>
      <link>https://journals.ametsoc.org/view/journals/mwre/143/4/mwr-d-14-00108.1.xml</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">B7C4MEGR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tödter, Julian; Ahrens, Bodo (2015) A Second-Order Exact Ensemble Square Root Filter for Nonlinear Data Assimilation. Monthly Weather Review. 143</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-14-00108.1</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PZSG2CHW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brisson, Erwan; Demuzere, Matthias; Willems, Patrick; van Lipzig, Nicole P. M. (2015) Assessment of natural climate variability using a weather generator. Climate Dynamics. 44</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-014-2122-8</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VW8275TJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mieruch, S.; Feldmann, H.; Schädler, G.; Lenz, C.-J.; Kothe, S.; Kottmeier, C. (2014) The regional MiKlip decadal forecast ensemble for Europe: the added value of downscaling. Geoscientific Model Development. 7</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-7-2983-2014</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LCUZUB8D</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van Weverberg, Kwinten; Goudenhoofdt, Edouard; Blahak, Ulrich; Brisson, Erwan; Demuzere, Matthias; Marbaix, Philippe; van Ypersele, Jean-Pascal (2014) Comparison of one-moment and two-moment bulk microphysics for high-resolution climate simulations of intense precipitation. Atmospheric Research. 147-148</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2014.05.012</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZAWZ9ARS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhimal, Meghnath; O’Hara, Robert B.; Karki, Ramchandra; Thakur, Garib D.; Kuch, Ulrich; Ahrens, Bodo (2014) Spatio-temporal distribution of malaria and its association with climatic factors and vector-control interventions in two high-risk districts of Nepal. Malaria Journal. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2875-13-457</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LV7ETGNX</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wacker, Ulrike; Fiebig, Jens; Tödter, Julian; Schöne, Bernd R.; Bahr, André; Friedrich, Oliver; Tütken, Thomas; Gischler, Eberhard; Joachimski, Michael M. (2014) Empirical calibration of the clumped isotope paleothermometer using calcites of various origins. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta. 141</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2014.06.004</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RPU5FF8I</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, Bodo; Formayer, Herbert; Gobiet, Andreas; Heinrich, Georg; Hofstätter, Michael; Matulla, Christoph; Prein, Andreas F.; Truhetz, Heimo; Anders, Ivonne; Haslinger, Klaus; Nadeem, Imran; Suklitsch, Martin; Themeßl, Matthias (2014) Kapitel 4: Zukünftige Klimaentwicklung</title>
      <link>https://austriaca.at?arp=0x0031449d</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I3BFMV7J</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhimal, Meghnath; Ahrens, Bodo; Kuch, Ulrich (2014) Species composition, seasonal occurrence, habitat preference and altitudinal distribution of malaria and other disease vectors in eastern Nepal. Parasites &amp; Vectors. 7</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-014-0540-4</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AEXHD9S5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akhtar, N.; Brauch, J.; Dobler, A.; Béranger, K.; Ahrens, B. (2014) Medicanes in an ocean–atmosphere coupled regional climate model. Natural Hazards and Earth System Sciences. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/nhess-14-2189-2014</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LHMR859C</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhimal, Meghnath; Ahrens, Bodo; Kuch, Ulrich (2014) Malaria control in Nepal 1963–2012: challenges on the path towards elimination. Malaria Journal. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/1475-2875-13-241</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">F9U4GW8V</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van Pham, Trang; Brauch, Jennifer; Dieterich, Christian; Frueh, Barbara; Ahrens, Bodo (2014) New coupled atmosphere-ocean-ice system COSMO-CLM/NEMO: assessing air temperature sensitivity over the North and Baltic Seas. Oceanologia. 56</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5697/oc.56-2.167</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7RSS3U5G</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liakka, Johan; Colleoni, Florence; Ahrens, Bodo; Hickler, Thomas (2014) The impact of climate-vegetation interactions on the onset of the Antarctic ice sheet. Geophysical Research Letters. 41</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2013GL058994</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BYHTZNBB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kothe, S.; Lüthi, D.; Ahrens, B. (2014) Analysis of the West African Monsoon system in the regional climate model COSMO-CLM. International Journal of Climatology. 34</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.3702</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Z2KID4GL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brinckmann, Sven; Trentmann, Jörg; Ahrens, Bodo (2014) Homogeneity Analysis of the CM SAF Surface Solar Irradiance Dataset Derived from Geostationary Satellite Observations. Remote Sensing. 6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/rs6010352</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KNLVA7V6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kumar, Pankaj; Wiltshire, Andrew; Mathison, Camilla; Asharaf, Shakeel; Ahrens, Bodo; Lucas-Picher, Philippe; Christensen, Jens H.; Gobiet, Andreas; Saeed, Fahad; Hagemann, Stefan; Jacob, Daniela (2013) Downscaled climate change projections with uncertainty assessment over India using a high resolution multi-model approach. Science of The Total Environment. 468-469</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2013.01.051</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XXD955ZT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tang, Hui; Eronen, Jussi T.; Micheels, Arne; Ahrens, Bodo (2013) Strong interannual variation of the Indian summer monsoon in the Late Miocene. Climate Dynamics. 41</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-012-1655-y</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I933ZB7J</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kothe, Steffen; Panitz, Hans-Jürgen; Ahrens, Bodo (2014) Analysis of the radiation budget in regional climate simulations with COSMO-CLM for Africa. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2014/0527</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5AXA3BPH</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krähenmann, Stefan; Obregon, Andre; Müller, Richard; Trentmann, Jörg; Ahrens, Bodo (2013) A Satellite-Based Surface Radiation Climatology Derived by Combining Climate Data Records and Near-Real-Time Data. Remote Sensing. 5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/rs5094693</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZKSNQFUN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kothe, Steffen; Good, Elizabeth; Obregón, André; Ahrens, Bodo; Nitsche, Helga (2013) Satellite-Based Sunshine Duration for Europe. Remote Sensing. 5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/rs5062943</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SZVQEYPR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tang, Hui; Micheels, Arne; Eronen, Jussi T.; Ahrens, Bodo; Fortelius, Mikael (2013) Asynchronous responses of East Asian and Indian summer monsoons to mountain uplift shown by regional climate modelling experiments. Climate Dynamics. 40</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-012-1603-x</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9MSIDGB2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asharaf, Shakeel; Ahrens, Bodo (2013) Soil-moisture memory in the regional climate model COSMO-CLM during the Indian summer monsoon season. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 118</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jgrd.50429</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EKWV3GF9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krähenmann, S.; Ahrens, B. (2013) Spatial gridding of daily maximum and minimum 2 m temperatures supported by satellite observations. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics. 120</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00703-013-0237-9</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">87LRD6DY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pfeifroth, Uwe; Mueller, Richard; Ahrens, Bodo (2013) Evaluation of Satellite-Based and Reanalysis Precipitation Data in the Tropical Pacific. Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology. 52</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-12-049.1</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9P7BDUCN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pfeifroth, Uwe; Hollmann, Rainer; Ahrens, Bodo (2012) Cloud Cover Diurnal Cycles in Satellite Data and Regional Climate Model Simulations. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2012/0423</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KUMVJ8P2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asharaf, Shakeel; Dobler, Andreas; Ahrens, Bodo (2012) Soil Moisture–Precipitation Feedback Processes in the Indian Summer Monsoon Season. Journal of Hydrometeorology. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JHM-D-12-06.1</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GNJ8KM44</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tödter, Julian; Ahrens, Bodo (2012) Generalization of the Ignorance Score: Continuous Ranked Version and Its Decomposition. Monthly Weather Review. 140</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-11-00266.1</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HP28KMR7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dobler, A.; Ahrens, B. (2011) Four climate change scenarios for the Indian summer monsoon by the regional climate model COSMO-CLM. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 116</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2011JD016329</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YH5WFY4S</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dobler, Andreas; Müller, Richard; Ahrens, Bodo (2011) Development and evaluation of a simple method to estimate evaporation from satellite data. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2011/0256</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6BEC994U</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kalinka, F.; Ahrens, B. (2011) A modification of the mixed form of Richards equation and its application in vertically inhomogeneous soils. 6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/asr-6-123-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YAXU6WAY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asharaf, S.; Dobler, A.; Ahrens, B. (2011) Soil moisture initialization effects in the Indian monsoon system. 6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/asr-6-161-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UGWJ7SXK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucas-Picher, Philippe; Christensen, Jens H.; Saeed, Fahad; Kumar, Pankaj; Asharaf, Shakeel; Ahrens, Bodo; Wiltshire, Andrew J.; Jacob, Daniela; Hagemann, Stefan (2011) Can Regional Climate Models Represent the Indian Monsoon?. Journal of Hydrometeorology. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2011JHM1327.1</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">N3V7L3P4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dobler, A.; Ahrens, B. (2010) Analysis of the Indian summer monsoon system in the regional climate model COSMO-CLM. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 115</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2009JD013497</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">F6QIQVAW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B. (2003) Rainfall downscaling in an alpine watershed applying a multiresolution approach. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 108</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2001JD001485</link>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4Y64KHLT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jaun, S.; Ahrens, B. (2009) Evaluation of a probabilistic hydrometeorological forecast system. Hydrology and Earth System Sciences. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/hess-13-1031-2009</link>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">S998ISVL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, Bodo; Walser, André (2008) Information-Based Skill Scores for Probabilistic Forecasts. Monthly Weather Review. 136</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2007MWR1931.1</link>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MBDCR6DA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krähenmann, S.; Ahrens, B. (2010) On daily interpolation of precipitation backed with secondary information. 4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/asr-4-29-2010</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VCWUE4UF</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Casanova, Sophie; Ahrens, Bodo (2009) On the Weighting of Multimodel Ensembles in Seasonal and Short-Range Weather Forecasting. Monthly Weather Review. 137</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2009MWR2893.1</link>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DFFHUCPZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dobler, Andreas; Ahrens, Bodo (2008) Precipitation by a regional climate model and bias correction in Europe and South Asia. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2008/0306</link>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">WV5IN9YW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B.; Karstens, U.; Rockel, B.; Stuhlmann, R. (1998) On the validation of the atmospheric model REMO with ISCCP data and precipitation measurements using simple statistics. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics. 68</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/BF01030205</link>
      <category>1998</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VAP2BD6A</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haimberger, L.; Ahrens, B.; Hamelbeck, F.; Hantel, M. (2001) Impact of time sampling on atmospheric energy budget residuals. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics. 77</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s007030170025</link>
      <category>2001</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RECEDPGZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B. (2006) Distance in spatial interpolation of daily rain gauge data. Hydrology and Earth System Sciences. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/hess-10-197-2006</link>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9FPF5THA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B; Stix, M.; Thorn, M. On the depletion of lithium in the Sun</title>
      <link>https://adsabs.harvard.edu/full/1992A%26A...264..673A</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">88V746XN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B. (1999) Variational Data Assimilation for a Lorenz Model Usinga Non-Standard Genetic Algorithm. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics. 70</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s007030050036</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LV2QWPD6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B.; Jasper, K.; Gurtz, J. (2003) On ALADIN precipitation modeling and validation in an Alpine watershed. Annales Geophysicae. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/angeo-21-627-2003</link>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I95CM96Q</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B. (2003) Evaluation of precipitation forecasting with the limited area model ALADIN in an Alpine watershed. Meteorologische Zeitschrift (Berlin) 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2003/0012-0245</link>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TVN99F2S</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beck, A.; Ahrens, B.; Stadlbacher, K. (2004) Impact of nesting strategies in dynamical downscaling of reanalysis data. Geophysical Research Letters. 31</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2004GL020115</link>
      <category>2004</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">B7WJWW3D</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beck, Alexander; Ahrens, Bodo (2004) Multiresolution evaluation of precipitation forecasts over the European Alps. Meteorologische Zeitschrift. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2004/0013-0055</link>
      <category>2004</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">WYHISCA9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dorninger, Manfred; Gorgas, Theresa; Beck, Alexander; Ahrens, Bodo; Loibl, Wolfgang; Steinacker, Reinhold (2005) EVALUATION OF RETROSPECTIVE REGIONAL CLIMATE MODEL RUNS WITH VERA WITHIN THE PROJECT RECLIP:MORE. Hrvatski meteorološki časopis. 40</title>
      <link>https://hrcak.srce.hr/64705</link>
      <category>2005</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NA2EZ32D</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jaun, S.; Ahrens, B.; Walser, A.; Ewen, T.; Schär, C. (2008) A probabilistic view on the August 2005 floods in the upper Rhine catchment. Natural Hazards and Earth System Sciences. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/nhess-8-281-2008</link>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">R73JY428</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, Bodo (2009) On Evaluation of Precipitation Fields with Rain Station Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-33236-7_10</link>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">H3U9B8YL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kothe, Steffen; Dobler, A.; Beck, A.; Ahrens, B. (2011) The radiation budget in a regional climate model. Climate Dynamics. 36</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-009-0733-2</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">53NTMBQA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B.; Jaun, S. (2007) On evaluation of ensemble precipitation forecasts with observation-based ensembles. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/adgeo-10-139-2007</link>
      <category>2007</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">M2R6GRYK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, B.; Beck, A. (2008) On upscaling of rain-gauge data for evaluating numerical weather forecasts. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics. 99</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00703-007-0261-8</link>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KN2RPGNZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kothe, S.; Ahrens, B. (2010) On the radiation budget in regional climate simulations for West Africa. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 115</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2010JD014331</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RQUIREHR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krähenmann, S.; Bissolli, P.; Rapp, J.; Ahrens, B. (2011) Spatial gridding of daily maximum and minimum temperatures in Europe. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics. 114</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00703-011-0160-x</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QZRD7JNV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krähenmann, Stefan; Kothe, Steffen; Panitz, Hans-Jürgen; Ahrens, Bodo (2013) Evaluation of daily maximum and minimum 2-m temperatures as simulated with the Regional Climate Model COSMO-CLM over Africa. Meteorologische Zeitschrift. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/0941-2948/2013/0468</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EV6DFRCC</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lauwaet, D.; De Ridder, K.; Saeed, S.; Brisson, E.; Chatterjee, F.; van Lipzig, N. P. M.; Maiheu, B.; Hooyberghs, H. (2016) Assessing the current and future urban heat island of Brussels. Urban Climate. 15</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.uclim.2015.11.008</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UCM4YFZH</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warwade, Pratibha; Sharma, Nayan; Pandey, Ashish; Ahrens, Bodo (2017) Analysis of Climate Variability in a Part of Brahmaputra River Basin in India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-10-1472-7_7</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KIDFHVTN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bowler, D. E.; Haase, P.; Kröncke, I.; Tackenberg, O.; Bauer, H. G.; Brendel, C.; Brooker, R. W.; Gerisch, M.; Henle, K.; Hickler, T.; Hof, C.; Klotz, S.; Kühn, I.; Matesanz, S.; O‘Hara, R.; Russell, D.; Schweiger, O.; Valladares, F.; Welk, E.; Wiemers, M.; Böhning-Gaese, K. (2015) A cross-taxon analysis of the impact of climate change on abundance trends in central Europe. Biological Conservation. 187</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2015.03.034</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FNSE48YB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saeed, Sajjad; Brisson, Erwan; Demuzere, Matthias; Tabari, Hossein; Willems, Patrick; van Lipzig, Nicole P. M. (2017) Multidecadal convection permitting climate simulations over Belgium: sensitivity of future precipitation extremes. Atmospheric Science Letters. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asl.720</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4M2M59SB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soares, P. M. M.; Maraun, D.; Brands, S.; Jury, M. W.; Gutiérrez, J. M.; San-Martín, D.; Hertig, E.; Huth, R.; Belušić Vozila, A.; Cardoso, Rita M.; Kotlarski, S.; Drobinski, P.; Obermann-Hellhund, A. (2019) Process-based evaluation of the VALUE perfect predictor experiment of statistical downscaling methods. International Journal of Climatology. 39</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5911</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">L6RUESTC</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lengfeld, Katharina; Winterrath, Tanja; Junghänel, Thomas; Hafer, Mario; Becker, Andreas (2019) Characteristic spatial extent of hourly and daily precipitation events in Germany derived from 16 years of radar dataCharacteristic spatial extent of hourly and daily precipitation events in Germany derived from 16 years of radar data. Meteorologische Zeitschrift. 28</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2019/0964</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6V6XFJUY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akhtar, Naveed; Krug, Amelie; Brauch, Jennifer; Arsouze, Thomas; Dieterich, Christian; Ahrens, Bodo (2019) European marginal seas in a regional atmosphere–ocean coupled model and their impact on Vb-cyclones and associated precipitation. Climate Dynamics. 53</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-019-04906-x</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">58ETZBDT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philipp, Daniel; Stengel, Martin; Ahrens, Bodo (2020) Analyzing the Arctic Feedback Mechanism between Sea Ice and Low-Level Clouds Using 34 Years of Satellite Observations. Journal of Climate. 33</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0895.1</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">37N7NVXG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collier, Emily; Ban, Nikolina; Richter, Niklas; Ahrens, Bodo; Chen, Deliang; Chen, Xingchao; Lai, Hui-Wen; Leung, Ruby; Li, Lu; Medvedova, Alzbeta; Ou, Tinghai; Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Potter, Emily; Prein, Andreas F.; Sakaguchi, Koichi; Schroeder, Marie; Singh, Prashant; Sobolowski, Stefan; Sugimoto, Shiori; Tang, Jianping; Yu, Hongyong; Ziska, Catharina (2024) The first ensemble of kilometer-scale simulations of a hydrological year over the third pole. Climate Dynamics. 62</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-024-07291-2</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HBRDGXYV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamouda, Mostafa E.; Portal, Alice; Pasquero, Claudia (2024) Polar Vortex Disruptions by High Latitude Ocean Warming. Geophysical Research Letters. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2023GL107567</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YD7CGNDG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Indische Monsun - Typische Charakteristika sowie Änderungen im Klimawandel</title>
      <link>https://www.westermann.de/anlage/4663337/Der-Indische-Monsun-Typische-Charakteristika-sowie-Aenderungen-im-Klimawandel</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4M5BB7R8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarasova, Larisa; Ahrens, Bodo; Hoff, Amelie; Lall, Upmanu (2024) The Value of Large-Scale Climatic Indices for Monthly Forecasting Severity of Widespread Flooding Using Dilated Convolutional Neural Networks. Earth's Future. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2023EF003680</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KPWEG8QK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz, Bruno; Nguyen, Viet Dung; Guse, Björn; Han, Li; Guan, Xiaoxiang; Rakovec, Oldrich; Samaniego, Luis; Ahrens, Bodo; Vorogushyn, Sergiy (2024) Spatial counterfactuals to explore disastrous flooding. Environmental Research Letters. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad22b9</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FVDWIA4Q</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lohmann, Richard; Purr, Christopher; Ahrens, Bodo (2024) Northern Hemisphere Atmospheric Blocking in CMIP6 Climate Projections using a Hybrid Index. Journal of Climate. -1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-23-0589.1</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I82Z26DZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meijer, Niels; Licht, Alexis; Woutersen, Amber; Hoorn, Carina; Robin-Champigneul, Faez; Rohrmann, Alexander; Tagliavento, Mattia; Brugger, Julia; Kelemen, Fanni D.; Schauer, Andrew J.; Hren, Micheal T.; Sun, Aijun; Fiebig, Jens; Mulch, Andreas; Dupont-Nivet, Guillaume (2024) Proto-monsoon rainfall and greening in Central Asia due to extreme early Eocene warmth. Nature Geoscience. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-023-01371-4</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DUQEGG6R</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>de Toma, Vincenzo; Ciani, Daniele; Hesham Essa, Yassmin; Yang, Chunxue; Artale, Vincenzo; Pisano, Andrea; Cavaliere, Davide; Santoleri, Rosalia; Storto, Andrea (2024) Skin sea surface temperature schemes in coupled ocean–atmosphere modelling: the impact of chlorophyll-interactive e-folding depth. Geoscientific Model Development. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-5145-2024</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">CHNMQ3K3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matho Lontio, S. L.; Komkoua Mbienda, A. J.; Guenang, G. M.; Demeko Yemih, P.; Xing Yan; Vondou, D. A.; Ahrens, B.; Dey, S.; Giorgi, F. (2024) Investigation of aerosol effects on diurnal cycle of precipitation amount, frequency and intensity over Central Africa. Climate Dynamics. 62</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-024-07303-1</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XXR892LL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essa, Y.H.; Madonna, F. (2024) Estimating climate extreme indices and the related uncertainties using U. S. Climate Reference Network (USCRN) near-surface temperature. Il Nuovo Cimento C. 47</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1393/ncc/i2024-24310-x</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">77549HJ6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singh, Prashant; Ahrens, Bodo (2023) Modeling Lightning Activity in the Third Pole Region: Performance of a km-Scale ICON-CLM Simulation. Atmosphere. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos14111655</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AS9N4CDP</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portal, Alice; D'Andrea, Fabio; Davini, Paolo; Hamouda, Mostafa E.; Pasquero, Claudia (2023) Atmospheric response to cold wintertime Tibetan Plateau conditions over eastern Asia in climate models. Weather and Climate Dynamics. 4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/wcd-4-809-2023</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9BNGU2MS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kelemen, Fanni Dora; Steinig, Sebastian; de Boer, Agatha; Zhu, Jiang; Chan, Wing-Le; Niezgodzki, Igor; Hutchinson, David K.; Knorr, Gregor; Abe-Ouchi, Ayako; Ahrens, Bodo (2023) Meridional Heat Transport in the DeepMIP Eocene Ensemble: Non-CO2 and CO2 Effects. Paleoceanography and Paleoclimatology. 38</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2022PA004607</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">WFACJHDS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wasserverwalter, Bueroheld (2023) Fachartikel HyWa Heft 5, 2023 – Ahrens et al. \textbar HyWa</title>
      <link>https://www.hywa-online.de/?wpdmpro=fachartikel-hywa-heft-5-2023-ahrens-et-al</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">F96GJ9JT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zittis, George; Ahrens, Bodo; Obermann-Hellhund, Anika; Giannakis, Elias; Risto, Danny; Agulles Gamez, Miguel; Jorda, Gabriel; Quesada Peña, Mónica; Lora Rodríguez, Veronica; Guersi Sauret, Jose Luis; Lionello, Piero; Briche, Elodie; Collignan, Julie; Grätz, Matthias; Arikas, Damian; Stylianou, Constantinos; Neophytou, Haris; Serghides, Despina (2023) Maritime transport and regional climate change impacts in large EU islands and archipelagos. Euro-Mediterranean Journal for Environmental Integration. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41207-023-00370-6</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">W3G8A4LE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valmassoi, Arianna; Keller, Jan D.; Kleist, Daryl T.; English, Stephen; Ahrens, Bodo; Ďurán, Ivan Bašták; Bauernschubert, Elisabeth; Bosilovich, Michael G.; Fujiwara, Masatomo; Hersbach, Hans; Lei, Lili; Löhnert, Ulrich; Mamnun, Nabir; Martin, Cory R.; Moore, Andrew; Niermann, Deborah; Ruiz, Juan José; Scheck, Leonhard (2023) Current Challenges and Future Directions in Data Assimilation and Reanalysis. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. 104</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-21-0331.1</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">M5EPPUE5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kramer, Isabelle Marie; Pfenninger, Markus; Feldmeyer, Barbara; Dhimal, Meghnath; Gautam, Ishan; Shreshta, Pramod; Baral, Sunita; Phuyal, Parbati; Hartke, Juliane; Magdeburg, Axel; Groneberg, David A.; Ahrens, Bodo; Müller, Ruth; Waldvogel, Ann-Marie (2023) Genomic profiling of climate adaptation in Aedes aegypti along an altitudinal gradient in Nepal indicates nongradual expansion of the disease vector. Molecular Ecology. 32</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.16752</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RSL3R5M7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prein, Andreas F.; Ban, Nikolina; Ou, Tinghai; Tang, Jianping; Sakaguchi, Koichi; Collier, Emily; Jayanarayanan, Sanjay; Li, Lu; Sobolowski, Stefan; Chen, Xingchao; Zhou, Xu; Lai, Hui-Wen; Sugimoto, Shiori; Zou, Liwei; Hasson, Shabeh ul; Ekstrom, Marie; Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Ahrens, Bodo; Stuart, Romilly; Steen-Larsen, Hans Christian; Leung, Ruby; Belusic, Danijel; Kukulies, Julia; Curio, Julia; Chen, Deliang (2023) Towards Ensemble-Based Kilometer-Scale Climate Simulations over the Third Pole Region. Climate Dynamics. 60</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-022-06543-3</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TL5C5XQS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Müller, Sebastian K.; Caillaud, Cécile; Chan, Steven; de Vries, Hylke; Bastin, Sophie; Berthou, Ségolène; Brisson, Erwan; Demory, Marie-Estelle; Feldmann, Hendrik; Goergen, Klaus; Kartsios, Stergios; Lind, Petter; Keuler, Klaus; Pichelli, Emanuela; Raffa, Mario; Tölle, Merja H.; Warrach-Sagi, Kirsten (2023) Evaluation of Alpine-Mediterranean precipitation events in convection-permitting regional climate models using a set of tracking algorithms. Climate Dynamics. 61</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-022-06555-z</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JG2WTCR2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portal, Alice; Pasquero, Claudia; D’Andrea, Fabio; Davini, Paolo; Hamouda, Mostafa E.; Rivière, Gwendal (2022) Influence of Reduced Winter Land–Sea Contrast on the Midlatitude Atmospheric Circulation. Journal of Climate. 35</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-21-0941.1</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EP7RCFWS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diez-Sierra, Javier; Iturbide, Maialen; Gutiérrez, José M.; Fernández, Jesús; Milovac, Josipa; Cofiño, Antonio S.; Cimadevilla, Ezequiel; Nikulin, Grigory; Levavasseur, Guillaume; Kjellström, Erik; Bülow, Katharina; Horányi, András; Brookshaw, Anca; García-Díez, Markel; Pérez, Antonio; Baño-Medina, Jorge; Ahrens, Bodo; Alias, Antoinette; Ashfaq, Moetasim; Bukovsky, Melissa; Buonomo, Erasmo; Caluwaerts, Steven; Chou, Sin Chan; Christensen, Ole B.; Ciarlò, James M.; Coppola, Erika; Corre, Lola; Demory, Marie-Estelle; Djurdjevic, Vladimir; Evans, Jason P.; Fealy, Rowan; Feldmann, Hendrik; Jacob, Daniela; Jayanarayanan, Sanjay; Katzfey, Jack; Keuler, Klaus; Kittel, Christoph; Kurnaz, Mehmet Levent; Laprise, René; Lionello, Piero; McGinnis, Seth; Mercogliano, Paola; Nabat, Pierre; Önol, Barış; Ozturk, Tugba; Panitz, Hans-Jürgen; Paquin, Dominique; Pieczka, Ildikó; Raffaele, Francesca; Remedio, Armelle Reca; Scinocca, John; Sevault, Florence; Somot, Samuel; Steger, Christian; Tangang, Fredolin; Teichmann, Claas; Termonia, Piet; Thatcher, Marcus; Torma, Csaba; Van Meijgaard, Erik; Vautard, Robert; Warrach-Sagi, Kirsten; Winger, Katja; Zittis, George (2022) The Worldwide C3S CORDEX Grand Ensemble: A Major Contribution to Assess Regional Climate Change in the IPCC AR6 Atlas. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. 103</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-22-0111.1</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">G59DNGWF</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risto, Danny; Fröhlich, Kristina; Ahrens, Bodo (2022) Snow Representation over Siberia in Operational Seasonal Forecasting Systems. Atmosphere. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos13071002</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AFYWA5I8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obermann-Hellhund, Anika (2022) State of the Simulation of Mesoscale Winds in the Mediterranean and Opportunities for Improvements. Atmosphere. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos13071007</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LI2S2B2S</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macdonald, Elena; Merz, Bruno; Guse, Björn; Wietzke, Luzie; Ullrich, Sophie; Kemter, Matthias; Ahrens, Bodo; Vorogushyn, Sergiy (2022) Event and Catchment Controls of Heavy Tail Behavior of Floods. Water Resources Research. 58</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2021WR031260</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XS9X47WE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purr, Christopher; Brisson, Erwan; Schlünzen, K. Heinke; Ahrens, Bodo (2022) Convective rain cell properties and the resulting precipitation scaling in a warm-temperate climate. Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society. 148</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.4277</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AZHR4SJY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krug, Amelie; Aemisegger, Franziska; Sprenger, Michael; Ahrens, Bodo (2022) Moisture sources of heavy precipitation in Central Europe in synoptic situations with Vb-cyclones. Climate Dynamics. 59</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-022-06256-7</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PHYSMTML</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>González, Yen E. Lam; Garcia, Carmen; Hernández, Matías M. González; Leon, Carmelo J. (2021) Downscaling climate change impacts, socio-economic implications and alternative adaptation pathways for islands and outermost regions</title>
      <link>https://zenodo.org/records/5141549</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VFFETMWW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, Bodo; Leps, Nora (2021) Sensitivity of Convection Permitting Simulations to Lateral Boundary Conditions in Idealized Experiments. Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2021MS002519</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">A7QPKCLG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sørland, Silje Lund; Brogli, Roman; Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Russo, Emmanuele; Van de Walle, Jonas; Ahrens, Bodo; Anders, Ivonne; Bucchignani, Edoardo; Davin, Edouard L.; Demory, Marie-Estelle; Dosio, Alessandro; Feldmann, Hendrik; Früh, Barbara; Geyer, Beate; Keuler, Klaus; Lee, Donghyun; Li, Delei; van Lipzig, Nicole P. M.; Min, Seung-Ki; Panitz, Hans-Jürgen; Rockel, Burkhardt; Schär, Christoph; Steger, Christian; Thiery, Wim (2021) COSMO-CLM regional climate simulations in the Coordinated Regional Climate Downscaling Experiment (CORDEX) framework: a review. Geoscientific Model Development. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-14-5125-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3KADHQW6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhimal, Meghnath; Kramer, Isabelle Marie; Phuyal, Parbati; Budhathoki, Shyam Sundar; Hartke, Juliane; Ahrens, Bodo; Kuch, Ulrich; Groneberg, David A.; Nepal, Santosh; Liu, Qi-Yong; Huang, Cun-Rui; CissÉ, Guéladio; Ebi, Kristie L.; KlingelhÖfer, Doris; Müller, Ruth (2021) Climate change and its association with the expansion of vectors and vector-borne diseases in the Hindu Kush Himalayan region: A systematic synthesis of the literature. Advances in Climate Change Research. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.accre.2021.05.003</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AEIKMYKD</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brisson, Erwan; Blahak, Ulrich; Lucas-Picher, Philippe; Purr, Christopher; Ahrens, Bodo (2021) Contrasting lightning projection using the lightning potential index adapted in a convection-permitting regional climate model. Climate Dynamics. 57</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-021-05791-z</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">T96PTCS5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You, Qinglong; Cai, Ziyi; Pepin, Nick; Chen, Deliang; Ahrens, Bodo; Jiang, Zhihong; Wu, Fangying; Kang, Shichang; Zhang, Ruonan; Wu, Tonghua; Wang, Pengling; Li, Mingcai; Zuo, Zhiyan; Gao, Yanhong; Zhai, Panmao; Zhang, Yuqing (2021) Warming amplification over the Arctic Pole and Third Pole: Trends, mechanisms and consequences. Earth-Science Reviews. 217</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2021.103625</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">J7WI6H2I</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krug, Amelie; Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Primo, Cristina; Ahrens, Bodo (2021) Heavy Vb‑cyclone precipitation: a transfer entropy application showcase. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2021/1071</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RZ85GP72</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kramer, Isabelle Marie; Pfeiffer, Marie; Steffens, Oliver; Schneider, Friederike; Gerger, Viviane; Phuyal, Parbati; Braun, Markus; Magdeburg, Axel; Ahrens, Bodo; Groneberg, David A.; Kuch, Ulrich; Dhimal, Meghnath; Müller, Ruth (2021) The ecophysiological plasticity of Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus concerning overwintering in cooler ecoregions is driven by local climate and acclimation capacity. Science of The Total Environment. 778</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.146128</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JA33945P</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fröhlich, Kristina; Dobrynin, Mikhail; Isensee, Katharina; Gessner, Claudia; Paxian, Andreas; Pohlmann, Holger; Haak, Helmuth; Brune, Sebastian; Früh, Barbara; Baehr, Johanna (2021) The German Climate Forecast System: GCFS. Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2020MS002101</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DMNMKVJZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ban, Nikolina; Caillaud, Cécile; Coppola, Erika; Pichelli, Emanuela; Sobolowski, Stefan; Adinolfi, Marianna; Ahrens, Bodo; Alias, Antoinette; Anders, Ivonne; Bastin, Sophie; Belušić, Danijel; Berthou, Ségolène; Brisson, Erwan; Cardoso, Rita M.; Chan, Steven C.; Christensen, Ole Bøssing; Fernández, Jesús; Fita, Lluís; Frisius, Thomas; Gašparac, Goran; Giorgi, Filippo; Goergen, Klaus; Haugen, Jan Erik; Hodnebrog, Øivind; Kartsios, Stergios; Katragkou, Eleni; Kendon, Elizabeth J.; Keuler, Klaus; Lavin-Gullon, Alvaro; Lenderink, Geert; Leutwyler, David; Lorenz, Torge; Maraun, Douglas; Mercogliano, Paola; Milovac, Josipa; Panitz, Hans-Juergen; Raffa, Mario; Remedio, Armelle Reca; Schär, Christoph; Soares, Pedro M. M.; Srnec, Lidija; Steensen, Birthe Marie; Stocchi, Paolo; Tölle, Merja H.; Truhetz, Heimo; Vergara-Temprado, Jesus; de Vries, Hylke; Warrach-Sagi, Kirsten; Wulfmeyer, Volker; Zander, Mar Janne (2021) The first multi-model ensemble of regional climate simulations at kilometer-scale resolution, part I: evaluation of precipitation. Climate Dynamics. 57</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-021-05708-w</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9NVLDJXK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purr, Christopher; Brisson, Erwan; Ahrens, Bodo (2021) Convective rain cell characteristics and scaling in climate projections for Germany. International Journal of Climatology. 41</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.7012</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2GMVNGMX</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drücke, Jaqueline; Borsche, Michael; James, Paul; Kaspar, Frank; Pfeifroth, Uwe; Ahrens, Bodo; Trentmann, Jörg (2021) Climatological analysis of solar and wind energy in Germany using the Grosswetterlagen classification. Renewable Energy. 164</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2020.10.102</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2A5BVVSU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kramer, Isabelle Marie; Baral, Sunita; Gautam, Ishan; Braun, Markus; Magdeburg, Axel; Phuyal, Parbati; Kadel, Indira; Dhimal, Meghnath; Ahrens, Bodo; Groneberg, David Alexander; Müller, Ruth (2021) STtech: sampling and transport techniques for Aedes eggs during a sampling campaign in a low-resource setting. Entomologia Experimentalis et Applicata. 169</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/eea.13022</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">C2THYING</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Primo, Cristina; Sørland, Silje; Ahrens, Bodo (2020) The synergistic impact of ENSO and IOD on Indian summer monsoon rainfall in observations and climate simulations – an information theory perspective. Earth System Dynamics. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/esd-11-903-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EQSLC8DD</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You, Qinglong; Chen, Deliang; Wu, Fangying; Pepin, Nick; Cai, Ziyi; Ahrens, Bodo; Jiang, Zhihong; Wu, Zhiwei; Kang, Shichang; AghaKouchak, Amir (2020) Elevation dependent warming over the Tibetan Plateau: Patterns, mechanisms and perspectives. Earth-Science Reviews. 210</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2020.103349</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">25BT64LR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drobinski, Philippe; Da Silva, Nicolas; Bastin, Sophie; Mailler, Sylvain; Muller, Caroline; Ahrens, Bodo; Christensen, Ole B.; Lionello, Piero (2020) How warmer and drier will the Mediterranean region be at the end of the twenty-first century?. Regional Environmental Change. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10113-020-01659-w</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QJ2ZJVS6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kramer, Isabelle M.; Kreß, Aljoscha; Klingelhöfer, Doris; Scherer, Christian; Phuyal, Parbati; Kuch, Ulrich; Ahrens, Bodo; Groneberg, David A.; Dhimal, Meghnath; Müller, Ruth (2020) Does winter cold really limit the dengue vector Aedes aegypti in Europe?. Parasites &amp; Vectors. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-020-04054-w</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I4PBRJAR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krug, Amelie; Primo, Cristina; Fischer, Svenja; Schumann, Andreas; Ahrens, Bodo (2020) On the temporal variability of widespread rain-on-snow floods. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2020/0989</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VSQL4X5Y</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahrens, Bodo; Meier, Thomas; Brisson, Erwan (2020) Diurnal Cycle of Precipitation in the Himalayan Foothills – Observations and Model Results</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-29684-1_5</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JSWH6268</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coppola, Erika; Sobolowski, Stefan; Pichelli, E.; Raffaele, F.; Ahrens, B.; Anders, I.; Ban, N.; Bastin, S.; Belda, M.; Belusic, D.; Caldas-Alvarez, A.; Cardoso, R. M.; Davolio, S.; Dobler, A.; Fernandez, J.; Fita, L.; Fumiere, Q.; Giorgi, F.; Goergen, K.; Güttler, I.; Halenka, T.; Heinzeller, D.; Hodnebrog, Ø.; Jacob, D.; Kartsios, S.; Katragkou, E.; Kendon, E.; Khodayar, S.; Kunstmann, H.; Knist, S.; Lavín-Gullón, A.; Lind, P.; Lorenz, T.; Maraun, D.; Marelle, L.; van Meijgaard, E.; Milovac, J.; Myhre, G.; Panitz, H.-J.; Piazza, M.; Raffa, M.; Raub, T.; Rockel, B.; Schär, C.; Sieck, K.; Soares, P. M. M.; Somot, S.; Srnec, L.; Stocchi, P.; Tölle, M. H.; Truhetz, H.; Vautard, R.; de Vries, H.; Warrach-Sagi, K. (2020) A first-of-its-kind multi-model convection permitting ensemble for investigating convective phenomena over Europe and the Mediterranean. Climate Dynamics. 55</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-018-4521-8</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JQ3P45MQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purr, Christopher; Brisson, Erwan; Ahrens, Bodo (2019) Convective Shower Characteristics Simulated with the Convection-Permitting Climate Model COSMO-CLM. Atmosphere. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos10120810</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5H7DVEGW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pothapakula, Praveen Kumar; Primo, Cristina; Ahrens, Bodo (2019) Quantification of Information Exchange in Idealized and Climate System Applications. Entropy. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/e21111094</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NCCUQFTJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kelemen, Fanni Dóra; Primo, Cristina; Feldmann, Hendrik; Ahrens, Bodo (2019) Added Value of Atmosphere-Ocean Coupling in a Century-Long Regional Climate Simulation. Atmosphere. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos10090537</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">WLYMUCEF</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Josipović, Lukas; Obermann-Hellhund, Anika; Brisson, Erwan; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) BORA IN REGIONAL CLIMATE MODELS: IMPACT OF MODEL RESOLUTION ON SIMULATIONS OF GAP WIND AND WAVE BREAKING. Hrvatski meteorološki časopis. 53</title>
      <link>https://hrcak.srce.hr/231266</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HNLZWE8S</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Primo, Cristina; Kelemen, Fanni D.; Feldmann, Hendrik; Akhtar, Naveed; Ahrens, Bodo (2019) A regional atmosphere–ocean climate system model (CCLMv5.0clm7-NEMOv3.3-NEMOv3.6) over Europe including three marginal seas: on its stability and performance. Geoscientific Model Development. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-12-5077-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DWY76IPN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leps, Nora; Brauch, Jennifer; Ahrens, Bodo (2019) Sensitivity of Limited Area Atmospheric Simulations to Lateral Boundary Conditions in Idealized Experiments. Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2019MS001625</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VUTJ4VXA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaspar, Frank; Borsche, Michael; Pfeifroth, Uwe; Trentmann, Jörg; Drücke, Jaqueline; Becker, Paul (2019) A climatological assessment of balancing effects and shortfall risks of photovoltaics and wind energy in Germany and Europe. 16</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/asr-16-119-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PTRJU885</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarasova, Larisa; Merz, Ralf; Kiss, Andrea; Basso, Stefano; Blöschl, Günter; Merz, Bruno; Viglione, Alberto; Plötner, Stefan; Guse, Björn; Schumann, Andreas; Fischer, Svenja; Ahrens, Bodo; Anwar, Faizan; Bárdossy, András; Bühler, Philipp; Haberlandt, Uwe; Kreibich, Heidi; Krug, Amelie; Lun, David; Müller-Thomy, Hannes; Pidoto, Ross; Primo, Cristina; Seidel, Jochen; Vorogushyn, Sergiy; Wietzke, Luzie (2019) Causative classification of river flood events. WIREs Water. 6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wat2.1353</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4RNLJ34V</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reyers, Mark; Feldmann, Hendrik; Mieruch, Sebastian; Pinto, Joaquim G.; Uhlig, Marianne; Ahrens, Bodo; Früh, Barbara; Modali, Kameswarrao; Laube, Natalie; Moemken, Julia; Müller, Wolfgang; Schädler, Gerd; Kottmeier, Christoph (2019) Development and prospects of the regional MiKlip decadal prediction system over Europe: predictive skill, added value of regionalization, and ensemble size dependency. Earth System Dynamics. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/esd-10-171-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AS38AFJP</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belušić Vozila, Andreina; Güttler, Ivan; Ahrens, Bodo; Obermann-Hellhund, Anika; Telišman Prtenjak, Maja (2019) Wind Over the Adriatic Region in CORDEX Climate Change Scenarios. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 124</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD028552</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NLARFQR8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pham, Trang Van; Brauch, Jennifer; Früh, Barbara; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) Added decadal prediction skill with the coupled regional climate model COSMO-CLM/NEMO. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2018/0872</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HXGM7HZG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bajnai, David; Fiebig, Jens; Tomašových, Adam; Milner Garcia, Sara; Rollion-Bard, Claire; Raddatz, Jacek; Löffler, Niklas; Primo-Ramos, Cristina; Brand, Uwe (2018) Assessing kinetic fractionation in brachiopod calcite using clumped isotopes. Scientific Reports. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-17353-7</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9PWZF7IW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brisson, Erwan; Brendel, Christoph; Herzog, Stephan; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) Lagrangian evaluation of convective shower characteristics in a convection-permitting model. Meteorologische Zeitschrift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2017/0817</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BLIA4HDA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obermann-Hellhund, Anika; Conte, Dario; Somot, Samuel; Torma, Csaba Zsolt; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) Mistral and Tramontane wind systems in climate simulations from 1950 to 2100. Climate Dynamics. 50</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3635-8</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3SP4GIZ5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somot, Samuel; Ruti, Paolo; Ahrens, Bodo; Coppola, Erika; Jordà, Gabriel; Sannino, Gianmaria; Solmon, Fabien (2018) Editorial for the Med-CORDEX special issue. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-018-4325-x</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">IAVRZSUU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obermann-Hellhund, Anika; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) Mistral and tramontane simulations with changing resolution of orography. Atmospheric Science Letters. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asl.848</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8DV23UGJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akhtar, Naveed; Brauch, Jennifer; Ahrens, Bodo (2018) Climate modeling over the Mediterranean Sea: impact of resolution and ocean coupling. Climate Dynamics. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3570-8</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SG84977D</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 08:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>