<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AG Engel Publikationen (IAU)</title>
    <link>https://www.iau.uni-frankfurt.de</link>
    <description>Publikationen der AG Engel, Institut für Atmosphäre und Umwelt (IAU)</description>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Zotero Feed Generator Script (AG Engel)</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://184467gianluca.github.io/institut-zotero-feed/AG_Engel_zotero_rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kolonjari, F.; Sheese, P. E.; Walker, K. A.; Boone, C. D.; Plummer, D. A.; Engel, A.; Montzka, S. A.; Oram, D. E.; Schuck, T.; Stiller, G. P.; Toon, G. C. (2024) Validation of Atmospheric Chemistry Experiment Fourier Transform Spectrometer (ACE-FTS) chlorodifluoromethane (HCFC-22) in the upper troposphere and lower stratosphere. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-17-2429-2024</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JHYSQSI4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ziereis, H.; Hoor, P.; Grooß, J.-U.; Zahn, A.; Stratmann, G.; Stock, P.; Lichtenstern, M.; Krause, J.; Bense, V.; Afchine, A.; Rolf, C.; Woiwode, W.; Braun, M.; Ungermann, J.; Marsing, A.; Voigt, C.; Engel, A.; Sinnhuber, B.-M.; Oelhaf, H. (2022) Redistribution of total reactive nitrogen in the lowermost Arctic stratosphere during the cold winter 2015/2016. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-3631-2022</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JC7YFTC5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamer, P. D.; Marécal, V.; Hossaini, R.; Pirre, M.; Krysztofiak, G.; Ziska, F.; Engel, A.; Sala, S.; Keber, T.; Bönisch, H.; Atlas, E.; Krüger, K.; Chipperfield, M.; Catoire, V.; Samah, A. A.; Dorf, M.; Siew Moi, P.; Schlager, H.; Pfeilsticker, K. (2021) Cloud-scale modelling of the impact of deep convection on the fate of oceanic bromoform in the troposphere: a case study over the west coast of Borneo. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-16955-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">B6YT5DKA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western, L. M.; Redington, A. L.; Manning, A. J.; Trudinger, C. M.; Hu, L.; Henne, S.; Fang, X.; Kuijpers, L. J. M.; Theodoridi, C.; Godwin, D. S.; Arduini, J.; Dunse, B.; Engel, A.; Fraser, P. J.; Harth, C. M.; Krummel, P. B.; Maione, M.; Mühle, J.; O'Doherty, S.; Park, H.; Park, S.; Reimann, S.; Salameh, P. K.; Say, D.; Schmidt, R.; Schuck, T.; Siso, C.; Stanley, K. M.; Vimont, I.; Vollmer, M. K.; Young, D.; Prinn, R. G.; Weiss, R. F.; Montzka, S. A.; Rigby, M. (2022) A renewed rise in global HCFC-141b emissions between 2017–2021. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-9601-2022</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9DX6RT5T</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schuck, T. J.; Degen, J.; Hintsa, E.; Hoor, P.; Jesswein, M.; Keber, T.; Kunkel, D.; Moore, F.; Obersteiner, F.; Rigby, M.; Wagenhäuser, T.; Western, L. M.; Zahn, A.; Engel, A. (2024) The interhemispheric gradient of SF₆ in the upper troposphere. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 24</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-689-2024</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9FSWN9NM</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wagenhäuser, T.; Jesswein, M.; Keber, T.; Schuck, T.; Engel, A. (2023) Mean age from observations in the lowermost stratosphere: an improved method and interhemispheric differences. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 23</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-3887-2023</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ETVAHU5Q</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bergamaschi, Peter; Frankenberg, Christian; Meirink, Jan Fokke; Krol, Maarten; Villani, M. Gabriella; Houweling, Sander; Dentener, Frank; Dlugokencky, Edward J.; Miller, John B.; Gatti, Luciana V.; Engel, Andreas; Levin, Ingeborg (2009) Inverse modeling of global and regional CH4 emissions using SCIAMACHY satellite retrievals. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 114</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2009jd012287</link>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7VR5PK82</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boenisch, H.; Engel, A.; Birner, Th; Hoor, P.; Tarasick, D. W.; Ray, E. A. (2011) On the structural changes in the Brewer-Dobson circulation after 2000. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-11-3937-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RFP7U2EZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bauer, R.; Engel, A.; Franken, H.; Klein, E.; Kulessa, G.; Schiller, C.; Schmidt, U.; Borchers, R.; Lee, J. (1994) Monitoring the Vertical Structure of the Arctic Polar Vortex over Northern Scandinavia during Easoe - Regular N2O Profile Observations. Geophysical Research Letters. 21</title>
      <category>1994</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">R9M6PYI3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boenisch, H.; Engel, A.; Curtius, J.; Birner, Th; Hoor, P. (2009) Quantifying transport into the lowermost stratosphere using simultaneous in-situ measurements of SF₆ and CO₂. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 9</title>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DIHIG4K7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bujok, O.; Tan, V.; Klein, E.; Nopper, R.; Bauer, R.; Engel, A.; Gerhards, M. T.; Afchine, A.; McKenna, D. S.; Schmidt, U.; Wienhold, F. G.; Fischer, H. (2001) GHOST - A novel airborne gas chromatograph for in situ measurements of long-lived tracers in the lower stratosphere: Method and applications. Journal of Atmospheric Chemistry. 39</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1023/a:1010789715871</link>
      <category>2001</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MUVQVC7K</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brinckmann, S.; Engel, A.; Boenisch, H.; Quack, B.; Atlas, E. (2012) Short-lived brominated hydrocarbons - observations in the source regions and the tropical tropopause layer. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-12-1213-2012</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7SFGSFL7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Butz, A.; Boesch, H.; Camy-Peyret, C.; Dorf, M.; Engel, A.; Payan, S.; Pfeilsticker, K. (2007) Observational constraints on the kinetics of the ClO-BrO and ClO-ClO ozone loss cycles in the Arctic winter stratosphere. Geophysical Research Letters. 34</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2006gl028718</link>
      <category>2007</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6ZUQPB8G</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirkov, M.; Stiller, G. P.; Laeng, A.; Kellmann, S.; von Clarmann, T.; Boone, C.; Elkins, J. W.; Engel, A.; Glatthor, N.; Grabowski, U.; Harth, C. M.; Kiefer, M.; Kolonjari, F.; Krummel, P. B.; Linden, A.; Lunder, C. R.; Miller, B. R.; Montzka, S. A.; Mühle, J.; O'Doherty, S.; Orphal, J.; Prinn, R. G.; Toon, G.; Vollmer, M. K.; Walker, K. A.; Weiss, R. F.; Wiegele, A.; Young, D. (2015) Global HCFC-22 measurements with MIPAS: retrieval, validation, climatologies and trends. Atmos. Chem. Phys. Discuss.. 15</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acpd-15-14783-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZA9H8QRU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirkov, M.; Stiller, G. P.; Laeng, A.; Kellmann, S.; von Clarmann, T.; Boone, C. D.; Elkins, J. W.; Engel, A.; Glatthor, N.; Grabowski, U.; Harth, C. M.; Kiefer, M.; Kolonjari, F.; Krummel, P. B.; Linden, A.; Lunder, C. R.; Miller, B. R.; Montzka, S. A.; Mühle, J.; O'Doherty, S.; Orphal, J.; Prinn, R. G.; Toon, G.; Vollmer, M. K.; Walker, K. A.; Weiss, R. F.; Wiegele, A.; Young, D. (2016) Global HCFC-22 measurements with MIPAS: retrieval, validation, global distribution and its evolution over 2005–2012. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 16</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-3345-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9M9QT7P3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clerbaux and Cunnold, C.; Authors, D. M. Cunnold; Anderson, J.; Engel, A.; Fraser, P. J.; Mahieu, E.; Manning, A.; Miller, J.; Montzka, S. A.; Nassar, R.; Prinn, R.; Reimann, S.; Rinsland, C. P.; Simmonds, P.; Verdonik, D.; Weiss, R.; Wuebbles, D.; Yokouchi, Y. (2007) Long-lived compounds, Chapter 1 in Scientific Assessment of Ozone Depletion: 2006, Global Ozone Research and Monitoring Project—Report No. 50</title>
      <category>2007</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MZHLWVUN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chabrillat, S.; Vigouroux, C.; Christophe, Y.; Engel, A.; Errera, Q.; Minganti, D.; Monge-Sanz, B. M.; Segers, A.; Mahieu, E. (2018) Comparison of mean age of air in five reanalyses using the BASCOE transport model. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-14715-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KVUK3TQP</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diallo, M.; Legras, B.; Ray, E.; Engel, A.; Añel, J. A. (2017) Global distribution of CO₂ in the upper troposphere and stratosphere. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-17-3861-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ACM6FJUT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dorf, M.; Boesch, H.; Butz, A.; Camy-Peyret, C.; Chipperfield, M. P.; Engel, A.; Goutail, F.; Grunow, K.; Hendrick, F.; Hrechanyy, S.; Naujokat, B.; Pommereau, J. P.; Van Roozendael, M.; Sioris, C.; Stroh, F.; Weidner, F.; Pfeilsticker, K. (2006) Balloon-borne stratospheric BrO measurements: comparison with Envisat/SCIAMACHY BrO limb profiles. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 6</title>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HNV4EDJZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eckert, E.; Laeng, A.; Lossow, S.; Kellmann, S.; Stiller, G.; von Clarmann, T.; Glatthor, N.; Höpfner, M.; Kiefer, M.; Oelhaf, H.; Orphal, J.; Funke, B.; Grabowski, U.; Haenel, F.; Linden, A.; Wetzel, G.; Woiwode, W.; Bernath, P. F.; Boone, C.; Dutton, G. S.; Elkins, J. W.; Engel, A.; Gille, J. C.; Kolonjari, F.; Sugita, T.; Toon, G. C.; Walker, K. A. (2015) MIPAS IMK/IAA CFC-11 (CCl3F) and CFC-12 (CCl2F2) measurements: accuracy, precision and long-term stability. Atmos. Meas. Tech. Discuss.. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amtd-8-7573-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EFGSVEN7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eckert, E.; von Clarmann, T.; Laeng, A.; Stiller, G. P.; Funke, B.; Glatthor, N.; Grabowski, U.; Kellmann, S.; Kiefer, M.; Linden, A.; Babenhauserheide, A.; Wetzel, G.; Boone, C.; Engel, A.; Harrison, J. J.; Sheese, P. E.; Walker, K. A.; Bernath, P. F. (2017) MIPAS IMK/IAA carbon tetrachloride (CCl₄) retrieval and first comparison with other instruments. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-10-2727-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HKYWXF7H</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Atlas, E. L. (2013) (Lead Authors), Bernath, P.F. Bönisch, H., Brown, A., Laube,J., Minschwaner, K.R., Montzka, S.A., O’Doherty, S. Prinn, R.G. Rigby, M. Schauffler, S.M. Volk, C.M., Yvon-Lewis, S. Inferred Lifetimes from Observed Trace-Gas Distributions, in SPARC Report N°6 (2013) Lifetimes of Stratospheric Ozone-Depleting Substances, Their Replacements, and Related Species; edited by M. K. W. Ko, P. A. Newman, S. Reimann, and S. E. Strahan</title>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4G5QWNRG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Bonisch, H.; Brunner, D.; Fischer, H.; Franke, H.; Gunther, G.; Gurk, C.; Hegglin, M.; Hoor, P.; Konigstedt, R.; Krebsbach, M.; Maser, R.; Parchatka, U.; Peter, T.; Schell, D.; Schiller, C.; Schmidt, U.; Spelten, N.; Szabo, T.; Weers, U.; Wernli, H.; Wetter, T.; Wirth, V. (2006) Highly resolved observations of trace gases in the lowermost stratosphere and upper troposphere from the Spurt project: an overview. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 6</title>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QUP5HFBI</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Ostermöller, J. (2017) Delayed Recovery of mid-latitude lower stratospheric Halogen Loading. Atmos. Chem. Phys. Discuss.. 2017</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-2017-550</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MXZN2MTQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Schwarzenberger, T.; Haase, H. P.; Grunow, K.; Abalichin, J.; Sala, S. (2015) Long term validation of ESA operational retrieval (version 6.0) of MIPAS Envisat vertical profiles of methane, nitrous oxides, CFC-11 and CFC-12 using balloon borne observations and trajectory matching. Atmos. Meas. Tech. Discuss.. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amtd-8-7455-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TDEQTHCB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Ostermöller, J.; Chipperfield, M. P.; Dhomse, S.; Jöckel, P. (2018) A refined method for calculating equivalent effective stratospheric chlorine. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-601-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">76AZV2A4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Schwarzenberger, T.; Haase, H. P.; Grunow, K.; Abalichin, J.; Sala, S. (2016) Long-term validation of ESA operational retrieval (version 6.0) of MIPAS Envisat vertical profiles of methane, nitrous oxide, CFC11, and CFC12 using balloon-borne observations and trajectory matching. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 9</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-9-1051-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FVN8HJV6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Ullrich, M.; Sitals, R.; Membrive, O.; Danis, F.; Crevoisier, C. (2017) Mean age of stratospheric air derived from AirCore observations. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-17-6825-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Q9894K78</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Mobius, T.; Bonisch, H.; Schmidt, U.; Heinz, R.; Levin, I.; Atlas, E.; Aoki, S.; Nakazawa, T.; Sugawara, S.; Moore, F.; Hurst, D.; Elkins, J.; Schauffler, S.; Andrews, A.; Boering, K. (2009) Age of stratospheric air unchanged within uncertainties over the past 30 years. Nature Geoscience. 2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/NGEO388</link>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">42UQH6TN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Mobius, T.; Haase, H. P.; Bonisch, H.; Wetter, T.; Schmidt, U.; Levin, I.; Reddmann, T.; Oelhaf, H.; Wetzel, G.; Grunow, K.; Huret, N.; Pirre, M. (2006) Observation of mesospheric air inside the arctic stratospheric polar vortex in early 2003. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 6</title>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6SIRMBX9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Muller, R.; Schmidt, U.; Carslaw, K. S.; Stachnik, R. A. (2000) Indications of heterogeneous chlorine activation on moderately cold aerosol based on chlorine observations in the Arctic stratosphere. Atmospheric Environment. 34</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1352-2310(00)00210-7</link>
      <category>2000</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">W4U6TCN3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Schmidt, U.; Stachnik, R. A. (1997) Partitioning between chlorine reservoir species deduced from observations in the arctic winter stratosphere. Journal of Atmospheric Chemistry. 27</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1023/a:1005781919448</link>
      <category>1997</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JGT4ACLY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Schiller, C.; Schmidt, U.; Borchers, R.; Ovarlez, H.; Ovarlez, J. (1996) The total hydrogen budget in the Arctic winter stratosphere during the European Arctic Stratospheric Ozone Experiment. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 101</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/95jd03766</link>
      <category>1996</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3YSML66J</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Schmidt, U. (1994) VERTICAL PROFILE MEASUREMENTS OF CARBONYLSULFIDE IN THE STRATOSPHERE. Geophysical Research Letters. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/94gl01461</link>
      <category>1994</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FP9ZZL55</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Strunk, M.; Muller, M.; Haase, H. P.; Poss, C.; Levin, I.; Schmidt, U. (2002) Temporal development of total chlorine in the high-latitude stratosphere based on reference distributions of mean age derived from CO2 and SF6. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 107</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2001jd000584</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XUDBCEAX</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, N.; Schmidt, U.; McKenna, D. (1998) Stratospheric trends of CFC-12 over the past two decades: Recent observational evidence of declining growth rates. Geophysical Research Letters. 25</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/98GL02520</link>
      <category>1998</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZDLNNYRV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fritsch, F.; Garny, H.; Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Eichinger, R. (2020) Sensitivity of age of air trends to the derivation method for non-linear increasing inert SF6. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-8709-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8E3RCIF3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engel, A.; Volk, C. M.; Haase, H. P.; Bonisch, H.; Mobius, T.; Schmidt, U.; Werner, A.; Wetter, T.; Ivanova, E.; Heinz, R.; Levin, I. (2003) Validation of tracer measurements by the Envisat chemistry instruments by means of in situ observations from balloon and aircraft. 16th Esa Symposium on European Rocket and Balloon Programmes and Related Research, Proceedings. 530</title>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MQJZZRKR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghysels, M.; Gomez, L.; Cousin, J.; Tran, H.; Amarouche, N.; Engel, A.; Levin, I.; Durry, G. (2014) Temperature dependences of air-broadening, air-narrowing and line-mixing coefficients of the methane nu(3) R(6) manifold lines-Application to in-situ measurements of atmospheric methane. Journal of Quantitative Spectroscopy &amp; Radiative Transfer. 133</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jqsrt.2013.08.003</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9LHEB39C</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenblatt, J. B.; Jost, H. J.; Loewenstein, M.; Podolske, J. R.; Bui, T. P.; Hurst, D. F.; Elkins, J. W.; Herman, R. L.; Webster, C. R.; Schauffler, S. M.; Atlas, E. L.; Newman, P. A.; Lait, L. R.; Muller, M.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U. (2002) Defining the polar vortex edge from an N2O : potential temperature correlation. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 107</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2001jd000575</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UNGV78LU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenblatt, J. B.; Jost, H. J.; Loewenstein, M.; Podolske, J. R.; Hurst, D. F.; Elkins, J. W.; Schauffler, S. M.; Atlas, E. L.; Herman, R. L.; Webster, C. R.; Bui, T. P.; Moore, F. L.; Ray, E. A.; Oltmans, S.; Vomel, H.; Blavier, J. F.; Sen, B.; Stachnik, R. A.; Toon, G. C.; Engel, A.; Muller, M.; Schmidt, U.; Bremer, H.; Pierce, R. B.; Sinnhuber, B. M.; Chipperfield, M.; Lefevre, F. (2002) Tracer-based determination of vortex descent in the 1999/2000 Arctic winter. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 107</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2001jd000937</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8YCRLR5D</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grooss, J. U.; Mueller, R.; Konopka, P.; Steinhorst, H. M.; Engel, A.; Moebius, T.; Volk, C. M. (2008) The impact of transport across the polar vortex edge on Match ozone loss estimates. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 8</title>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7IJPUXSF</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hauck, M.; Bönisch, H.; Hoor, P.; Keber, T.; Ploeger, F.; Schuck, T. J.; Engel, A. (2020) A convolution of observational and model data to estimate age of air spectra in the northern hemispheric lower stratosphere. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-8763-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">466Z9KBS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grooß, J.-U.; Günther, G.; Konopka, P.; Müller, R.; McKenna, D. S.; Stroh, F.; Vogel, B.; Engel, A.; Müller, M.; Hoppel, K.; Bevilacqua, R.; Richard, E.; Webster, C. R.; Elkins, J. W.; Hurst, D. F.; Romashkin, P. A.; Baumgardner, D. G. (2002) Simulation of ozone depletion in spring 2000 with the Chemical Lagrangian Model of the Stratosphere (CLaMS) Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 107</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2001JD000456</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">K63XISAU</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hall, B. D.; Engel, A.; Muehle, J.; Elkins, J. W.; Artuso, F.; Atlas, E.; Aydin, M.; Blake, D.; Brunke, E.-G.; Chiavarini, S.; Fraser, P. J.; Happell, J.; Krummel, P. B.; Levin, I.; Loewenstein, M.; Maione, M.; Montzka, S. A.; O'Doherty, S.; Reimann, S.; Rhoderick, G.; Saltzman, E. S.; Scheel, H. E.; Steele, L. P.; Vollmer, M. K.; Weiss, R. F.; Worthy, D.; Yokouchi, Y. (2014) Results from the International Halocarbons in Air Comparison Experiment (IHALACE) Atmospheric Measurement Techniques. 7</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-7-469-2014</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">X54NU6KB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamer, P. D.; Marécal, V.; Hossaini, R.; Pirre, M.; Warwick, N.; Chipperfield, M.; Samah, A. A.; Harris, N.; Robinson, A.; Quack, B.; Engel, A.; Krüger, K.; Atlas, E.; Subramaniam, K.; Oram, D.; Leedham, E.; Mills, G.; Pfeilsticker, K.; Sala, S.; Keber, T.; Bönisch, H.; Peng, L. K.; Nadzir, M. S. M.; Lim, P. T.; Mujahid, A.; Anton, A.; Schlager, H.; Catoire, V.; Krysztofiak, G.; Fühlbrügge, S.; Dorf, M.; Sturges, W. T. (2013) Modelling the chemistry and transport of bromoform within a sea breeze driven convective system during the SHIVA Campaign. Atmos. Chem. Phys. Discuss.. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acpd-13-20611-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">V3LYY3SB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hartmann, J. M.; Kochel, J. M.; Payan, S.; CamyPeyret, C.; Engel, A. (1997) CCl₂F₂ mixing ratio profiles in the 1995 Late Winter Arctic vortex from balloon-borne spectra. Geophysical Research Letters. 24</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/97gl02522</link>
      <category>1997</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">A6V4HH9G</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hauck, M.; Fritsch, F.; Garny, H.; Engel, A. (2019) Deriving stratospheric age of air spectra using an idealized set of chemically active trace gases. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-5269-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8LUEBEH4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoker, J.; Obersteiner, F.; Bönisch, H.; Engel, A. (2015) Comparison of GC/time-of-flight MS with GC/quadrupole MS for halocarbon trace gas analysis. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-8-2195-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UZGULM9A</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hauck, M.; Fritsch, F.; Garny, H.; Engel, A. (2018) Deriving stratospheric age of air spectra using chemically active trace gases. Atmos. Chem. Phys. Discuss.. 2018</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-2018-991</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AEN6QLFV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hossaini, R.; Mantle, H.; Chipperfield, M. P.; Montzka, S. A.; Hamer, P.; Ziska, F.; Quack, B.; Krüger, K.; Tegtmeier, S.; Atlas, E.; Sala, S.; Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Keber, T.; Oram, D.; Mills, G.; Ordóñez, C.; Saiz-Lopez, A.; Warwick, N.; Liang, Q.; Feng, W.; Moore, F.; Miller, B. R.; Marécal, V.; Richards, N. A. D.; Dorf, M.; Pfeilsticker, K. (2013) Evaluating global emission inventories of biogenic bromocarbons. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-11819-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LQB3GC36</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hossaini, R.; Patra, P. K.; Leeson, A. A.; Krysztofiak, G.; Abraham, N. L.; Andrews, S. J.; Archibald, A. T.; Aschmann, J.; Atlas, E. L.; Belikov, D. A.; Boenisch, H.; Carpenter, L. J.; Dhomse, S.; Dorf, M.; Engel, A.; Feng, W.; Fuhlbruegge, S.; Griffiths, P. T.; Harris, N. R. P.; Hommel, R.; Keber, T.; Krueger, K.; Lennartz, S. T.; Maksyutov, S.; Mantle, H.; Mills, G. P.; Miller, B.; Montzka, S. A.; Moore, F.; Navarro, M. A.; Oram, D. E.; Pfeilsticker, K.; Pyle, J. A.; Quack, B.; Robinson, A. D.; Saikawa, E.; Saiz-Lopez, A.; Sala, S.; Sinnhuber, B.-M.; Taguchi, S.; Tegtmeier, S.; Lidster, R. T.; Wilson, C.; Ziska, F. (2016) A multi-model intercomparison of halogenated very short-lived substances (TransCom-VSLS): linking oceanic emissions and tropospheric transport for a reconciled estimate of the stratospheric source gas injection of bromine. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 16</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-9163-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UKYJ9RYM</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesswein, M.; Bozem, H.; Lachnitt, H. C.; Hoor, P.; Wagenhäuser, T.; Keber, T.; Schuck, T.; Engel, A. (2021) Comparison of inorganic chlorine in the Antarctic and Arctic lowermost stratosphere by separate late winter aircraft measurements. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-17225-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">H9J36L7Y</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoor, P.; Fischer, H.; Wong, S.; Engel, A.; Wetter, T. (1999) Intercomparison of airborne N₂O measurements using tunable diode laser absorption spectroscopy and in situ gas chromatography. Application of Tunable Diode and Other Infrared Sources for Atmospheric Studies and Industrial Processing Monitoring Ii. 3758</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.366442</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YNBUGUU2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesswein, M.; Fernandez, R. P.; Berná, L.; Saiz-Lopez, A.; Grooß, J. U.; Hossaini, R.; Apel, E. C.; Hornbrook, R. S.; Atlas, E. L.; Blake, D. R.; Montzka, S.; Keber, T.; Schuck, T.; Wagenhäuser, T.; Engel, A. (2022) Global seasonal distribution of CH2Br2 and CHBr3 in the upper troposphere and lower stratosphere. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-15049-2022</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RTFGQ4PH</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Johansson, S.; Woiwode, W.; Höpfner, M.; Friedl-Vallon, F.; Kleinert, A.; Kretschmer, E.; Latzko, T.; Orphal, J.; Preusse, P.; Ungermann, J.; Santee, M. L.; Jurkat-Witschas, T.; Marsing, A.; Voigt, C.; Giez, A.; Krämer, M.; Rolf, C.; Zahn, A.; Engel, A.; Sinnhuber, B. M.; Oelhaf, H. (2018) Airborne limb-imaging measurements of temperature, HNO3, O3, ClONO2, H2O and CFC-12 during the Arctic winter 2015/2016: characterization, in situ validation and comparison to Aura/MLS. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-11-4737-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">B8TSI8CT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jurkat, T.; Voigt, C.; Kaufmann, S.; Grooß, J. U.; Ziereis, H.; Dörnbrack, A.; Hoor, P.; Bozem, H.; Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Keber, T.; Hüneke, T.; Pfeilsticker, K.; Zahn, A.; Walker, K. A.; Boone, C. D.; Bernath, P. F.; Schlager, H. (2017) Depletion of ozone and reservoir species of chlorine and nitrogen oxide in the lower Antarctic polar vortex measured from aircraft. Geophysical Research Letters. 44</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2017GL073270</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4UWRVBV7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jurkat, T.; Voigt, C.; Kaufmann, S.; Zahn, A.; Sprenger, M.; Hoor, P.; Bozem, H.; Müller, S.; Dörnbrack, A.; Schlager, H.; Bönisch, H.; Engel, A. (2014) A quantitative analysis of stratospheric HCl, HNO3, and O3 in the tropopause region near the subtropical jet. Geophysical Research Letters. 41</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2013GL059159</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7LHBF9KR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanzawa, H.; Sugita, T.; Nakajima, H.; Bodeker, G. E.; Oelhaf, H.; Stowasser, M.; Wetzel, G.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U.; Levin, I.; Toon, G. C.; Sen, B.; Blavier, J. F.; Aoki, S.; Nakazawa, T.; Jucks, K. W.; Johnson, D. G.; Traub, W. A.; Camy-Peyret, C.; Payan, S.; Jeseck, P.; Murata, I.; Fukunishi, H.; von Konig, M.; Bremer, H.; Kullmann, H.; Park, J. H.; Pan, L. L.; Yokota, T.; Suzuki, M.; Shiotani, M.; Sasano, Y. (2003) Validation and data characteristics of nitrous oxide and methane profiles observed by the Improved Limb Atmospheric Spectrometer (ILAS) and processed with the Version 5.20 algorithm. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 108</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2002jd002458</link>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">U6XWSVPS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaufmann, M.; Blank, J.; Guggenmoser, T.; Ungermann, J.; Engel, A.; Ern, M.; Friedl-Vallon, F.; Gerber, D.; Grooß, J. U.; Guenther, G.; Höpfner, M.; Kleinert, A.; Kretschmer, E.; Latzko, Th; Maucher, G.; Neubert, T.; Nordmeyer, H.; Oelhaf, H.; Olschewski, F.; Orphal, J.; Preusse, P.; Schlager, H.; Schneider, H.; Schuettemeyer, D.; Stroh, F.; Suminska-Ebersoldt, O.; Vogel, B.; M. Volk, C.; Woiwode, W.; Riese, M. (2015) Retrieval of three-dimensional small-scale structures in upper-tropospheric/lower-stratospheric composition as measured by GLORIA. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-8-81-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FX3VAD42</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaiser, J.; Engel, A.; Borchers, R.; Rockmann, T. (2006) Probing stratospheric transport and chemistry with new balloon and aircraft observations of the meridional and vertical N2O isotope distribution. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 6</title>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LK5SU2ML</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keber, T.; Bönisch, H.; Hartick, C.; Hauck, M.; Lefrancois, F.; Obersteiner, F.; Ringsdorf, A.; Schohl, N.; Schuck, T.; Hossaini, R.; Graf, P.; Jöckel, P.; Engel, A. (2019) Bromine from short–lived source gases in the Northern Hemisphere UTLS. Atmos. Chem. Phys. Discuss.. 2019</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-2019-796</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FEE96STP</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keber, T.; Bönisch, H.; Hartick, C.; Hauck, M.; Lefrancois, F.; Obersteiner, F.; Ringsdorf, A.; Schohl, N.; Schuck, T.; Hossaini, R.; Graf, P.; Jöckel, P.; Engel, A. (2020) Bromine from short-lived source gases in the extratropical northern hemispheric upper troposphere and lower stratosphere (UTLS) Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-4105-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2TK52LK5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khaykin, S. M.; Engel, I.; Vömel, H.; Formanyuk, I. M.; Kivi, R.; Korshunov, L. I.; Krämer, M.; Lykov, A. D.; Meier, S.; Naebert, T.; Pitts, M. C.; Santee, M. L.; Spelten, N.; Wienhold, F. G.; Yushkov, V. A.; Peter, T. (2013) Arctic stratospheric dehydration – Part 1: Unprecedented observation of vertical redistribution of water. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-11503-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8LFEIAXC</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khosrawi, F.; Muller, R.; Irie, H.; Engel, A.; Toon, G. C.; Sen, B.; Aoki, S.; Nakazawa, T.; Traub, W. A.; Jucks, K. W.; Johnson, D. G.; Oelhaf, H.; Wetzel, G.; Sugita, T.; Kanzawa, H.; Yokota, T.; Nakajima, H.; Sasano, Y. (2004) Validation of CFC-12 measurements from the Improved Limb Atmospheric Spectrometer (ILAS) with the version 6.0 retrieval algorithm. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 109</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2003jd004325</link>
      <category>2004</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XEN3N5M2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kondo, Y.; Koike, M.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U.; Mueller, M.; Sugita, T.; Kanzawa, H.; Nakazawa, T.; Aoki, S.; Irie, H.; Toriyama, N.; Suzuki, T.; Sasano, Y. (1999) NOy-N2O correlation observed inside the Arctic vortex in February 1997: Dynamical and chemical effects. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 104</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/1999jd900020</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AVPN25R5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Konopka, Paul; Engel, Andreas; Funke, Bernd; Mueller, Rolf; Grooss, Jens-Uwe; Guenther, Gebhard; Wetter, Thomas; Stiller, Gabriele; von Clarmann, Thomas; Glatthor, Norbert; Oelhaf, Hermann; Wetzel, Gerald; Lopez-Puertas, Manuel; Pirre, Michel; Huret, Nathalie; Riese, Martin (2007) Ozone loss driven by nitrogen oxides and triggered by stratospheric warmings can outweigh the effect of halogens. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 112</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2006jd007064</link>
      <category>2007</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JWNX6K4A</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ko, M. K. W.; Newman, P.; Reimann, S.; Strahan, S. E.; Atlas, E. L.; Burkholder, J. B.; Chipperfield, M.; Engel, A.; Liang, Q.; Mellouki, W.; Plumb, R. A.; Stolarski, R. S.; Volk, C. M. (2013) Recommended Values for Steady-State Atmospheric Lifetimes and their Uncertainties , in SPARC Report N°6 (2013) Lifetimes of Stratospheric Ozone-Depleting Substances, Their Replacements, and Related Species; edited by M. K. W. Ko, P. A. Newman, S. Reimann, and S. E. Strahan</title>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LRSEIPLJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kondo, Y.; Schmidt, U.; Sugita, T.; Engel, A.; Koike, M.; Aimedieu, P.; Gunson, M. R.; Rodriguez, J. (1996) NOy correlation with N2O and CH4 in the midlatitude stratosphere. Geophysical Research Letters. 23</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/96gl00870</link>
      <category>1996</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">IFT4MK8Z</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krause, J.; Hoor, P.; Engel, A.; Plöger, F.; Grooß, J. U.; Bönisch, H.; Keber, T.; Sinnhuber, B. M.; Woiwode, W.; Oelhaf, H. (2018) Mixing and ageing in the polar lower stratosphere in winter 2015–2016. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-6057-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RVZBCDGG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krysztofiak, Gisèle; Catoire, Valéry; Hamer, Paul D.; Marécal, Virginie; Robert, Claude; Engel, Andreas; Bönisch, Harald; Grossmann, Katja; Quack, Birgit; Atlas, Elliot; Pfeilsticker, Klaus (2018) Evidence of convective transport in tropical West Pacific region during SHIVA experiment. Atmospheric Science Letters. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asl.798</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Z434U4IB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kuell, V.; Offermann, D.; Jarisch, M.; Schaeler, B.; Engel, A.; Claude, H.; Smit, H. G. J.; Ebel, A.; Feldmann, H. (2005) Tropopause region temperatures and CFC 11 mixing ratios from CRISTA 2. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 110</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2004jd005592</link>
      <category>2005</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BHLFH4WI</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laeng, A.; Plieninger, J.; von Clarmann, T.; Grabowski, U.; Stiller, G.; Eckert, E.; Glatthor, N.; Haenel, F.; Kellmann, S.; Kiefer, M.; Linden, A.; Lossow, S.; Deaver, L.; Engel, A.; Hervig, M.; Levin, I.; McHugh, M.; Noel, S.; Toon, G.; Walker, K. (2015) Validation of MIPAS IMK/IAA methane profiles. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques. 8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-8-5251-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4ZMFUH4C</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Engel, A. (2008) First atmospheric observations of three chlorofluorocarbons. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 8</title>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I9S4NDHI</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Engel, A.; Boenisch, H.; Moebius, T.; Sturges, W. T.; Brass, M.; Rockmann, T. (2010) Fractional release factors of long-lived halogenated organic compounds in the tropical stratosphere (vol 10, pg 1093, 2010) Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-10-4975-2010</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KT4AEIPI</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Engel, A.; Boenisch, H.; Moebius, T.; Sturges, W. T.; Brass, M.; Rockmann, T. (2010) Fractional release factors of long-lived halogenated organic compounds in the tropical stratosphere. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-10-1093-2010</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ELMBVH3J</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Kaiser, J.; Sturges, W. T.; Bonisch, H.; Engel, A. (2010) Chlorine Isotope Fractionation in the Stratosphere. Science. 329</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1191809</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QLK5SCNQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Engel, A.; Boenisch, H.; Moebius, T.; Worton, D. R.; Sturges, W. T.; Grunow, K.; Schmidt, U. (2008) Contribution of very short-lived organic substances to stratospheric chlorine and bromine in the tropics - a case study. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 8</title>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3V82C4GW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Keil, A.; Bönisch, H.; Engel, A.; Röckmann, T.; Volk, C. M.; Sturges, W. T. (2013) Observation-based assessment of stratospheric fractional release, lifetimes, and ozone depletion potentials of ten important source gases. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-2779-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZQV5GJ6V</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laube, J. C.; Martinerie, P.; Witrant, E.; Blunier, T.; Schwander, J.; Brenninkmeijer, C. A. M.; Schuck, T. J.; Bolder, M.; Roeckmann, T.; van der Veen, C.; Boenisch, H.; Engel, A.; Mills, G. P.; Newland, M. J.; Oram, D. E.; Reeves, C. E.; Sturges, W. T. (2010) Accelerating growth of HFC-227ea (1,1,1,2,3,3,3-heptafluoropropane) in the atmosphere. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-10-5903-2010</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">E36HU5VJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lee, J. M.; Sturges, W. T.; Penkett, S. A.; Oram, D. E.; Schmidt, U.; Engel, A.; Bauer, R. (1995) OBSERVED STRATOSPHERIC PROFILES AND STRATOSPHERIC LIFETIMES OF HCFC-141B AND HCFC-142B. Geophysical Research Letters. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/95gl01313</link>
      <category>1995</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZD24WDEW</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lefrancois, F.; Jesswein, M.; Thoma, M.; Engel, A.; Stanley, K.; Schuck, T. (2021) An indirect-calibration method for non-target quantification of trace gases applied to a time series of fourth-generation synthetic halocarbons at the Taunus Observatory (Germany) Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-14-4669-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">IX4M2A67</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leedham Elvidge, E.; Bönisch, H.; Brenninkmeijer, C. A. M.; Engel, A.; Fraser, P. J.; Gallacher, E.; Langenfelds, R.; Mühle, J.; Oram, D. E.; Ray, E. A.; Ridley, A. R.; Röckmann, T.; Sturges, W. T.; Weiss, R. F.; Laube, J. C. (2018) Evaluation of stratospheric age of air from CF4, C2F6, C3F8, CHF3, HFC-125, HFC-227ea and SF6; implications for the calculations of halocarbon lifetimes, fractional release factors and ozone depletion potentials. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-3369-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BD2NBB2Q</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Levin, I.; Naegler, T.; Heinz, R.; Osusko, D.; Cuevas, E.; Engel, A.; Ilmberger, J.; Langenfelds, R. L.; Neininger, B.; Rohden, C. v; Steele, L. P.; Weller, R.; Worthy, D. E.; Zimov, S. A. (2010) The global SF6 source inferred from long-term high precision atmospheric measurements and its comparison with emission inventories. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-10-2655-2010</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YIWCYFVE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manning, A. J.; Redington, A. L.; Say, D.; O'Doherty, S.; Young, D.; Simmonds, P. G.; Vollmer, M. K.; Mühle, J.; Arduini, J.; Spain, G.; Wisher, A.; Maione, M.; Schuck, T. J.; Stanley, K.; Reimann, S.; Engel, A.; Krummel, P. B.; Fraser, P. J.; Harth, C. M.; Salameh, P. K.; Weiss, R. F.; Gluckman, R.; Brown, P. N.; Watterson, J. D.; Arnold, T. (2021) Evidence of a recent decline in UK emissions of HFCs determined by the InTEM inverse model and atmospheric measurements. Atmos. Chem. Phys. Discuss.. 2021</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-2021-261</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4ECSDWHC</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marsing, A.; Jurkat-Witschas, T.; Grooß, J. U.; Kaufmann, S.; Heller, R.; Engel, A.; Hoor, P.; Krause, J.; Voigt, C. (2019) Chlorine partitioning in the lowermost Arctic vortex during the cold winter 2015/2016. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-10757-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MYDLZCKA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membrive, O.; Crevoisier, C.; Sweeney, C.; Danis, F.; Hertzog, A.; Engel, A.; Bönisch, H.; Picon, L. (2017) AirCore-HR: a high-resolution column sampling to enhance the vertical description of CH₄ and CO₂. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-10-2163-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VQ43Z8T6</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muller, R.; Tilmes, S.; Grooss, J. U.; Engel, A.; Oelhaf, H.; Wetzel, G.; Huret, N.; Pirre, M.; Catoire, V.; Toon, G.; Nakajima, H. (2007) Impact of mesospheric intrusions on ozone-tracer relations in the stratospheric polar vortex. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 112</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/Artn%20D23307%20Doi%2010.1029/2006jd008315</link>
      <category>2007</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">J28QSSRQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Messerschmidt, J.; Geibel, M. C.; Blumenstock, T.; Chen, H.; Deutscher, N. M.; Engel, A.; Feist, D. G.; Gerbig, C.; Gisi, M.; Hase, F.; Katrynski, K.; Kolle, O.; Lavric, J. V.; Notholt, J.; Palm, M.; Ramonet, M.; Rettinger, M.; Schmidt, M.; Sussmann, R.; Toon, G. C.; Truong, F.; Warneke, T.; Wennberg, P. O.; Wunch, D.; Xueref-Remy, I. (2011) Calibration of TCCON column-averaged CO2: the first aircraft campaign over European TCCON sites. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-11-10765-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZIH7RSSH</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimann, Montzka and; Engel, A.; Krüger, K.; O’Doherty, S.; Sturges, W. T.; Blake, D.; Dorf, M.; Fraser, P.; Froidevaux, L.; Jucks, K.; Kreher, K.; Kurylo, M. J.; Mellouki, A.; Miller, J.; Nielsen, O.-J.; Orkin, V. L.; Prinn, R. G.; Rhew, R.; Santee, M. L.; Verdonik, D. (2011) Ozone-Depleting Substances (ODSs) and Related Chemicals, Chapter 1 in Scientific Assessment of Ozone Depletion: 2010, Global Ozone Research and Monitoring Project-Report No. 52, World Meteorological Organization, Geneva, Switzerland, 516p.</title>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7W63CEH4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muller, M.; Strunk, M.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U. (2000) Vertical profiles of long lived trace gases - A basis for the analysis of stratospheric dynamics. Chemistry and Radiation Changes in the Ozone Layer. 557</title>
      <category>2000</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YLL9SQEZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muller, R.; Schmidt, U.; Engel, A.; McKenna, D. S.; Proffitt, M. H. (2001) The O-3-N2O relation from balloon-borne observations as a measure of Arctic ozone loss in 1991/92. Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society. 127</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1256/smsqj.57414</link>
      <category>2001</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">UB3L7WB2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Müller, S.; Hoor, P.; Bozem, H.; Gute, E.; Vogel, B.; Zahn, A.; Bönisch, H.; Keber, T.; Krämer, M.; Rolf, C.; Riese, M.; Schlager, H.; Engel, A. (2016) Impact of the Asian monsoon on the extratropical lower stratosphere: trace gas observations during TACTS over Europe 2012. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 16</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-10573-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Y2YMNIRB</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obersteiner, F.; Bönisch, H.; Engel, A. (2016) An automated gas chromatography time-of-flight mass spectrometry instrument for the quantitative analysis of halocarbons in air. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 9</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-9-179-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QVURA5IA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oelhaf, Hermann; Sinnhuber, Björn-Martin; Woiwode, Wolfgang; Bönisch, Harald; Bozem, Heiko; Engel, Andreas; Fix, Andreas; Friedl-Vallon, Felix; Grooß, Jens-Uwe; Hoor, Peter; Johansson, Sören; Jurkat-Witschas, Tina; Kaufmann, Stefan; Krämer, Martina; Krause, Jens; Kretschmer, Erik; Lörks, Dominique; Marsing, Andreas; Orphal, Johannes; Pfeilsticker, Klaus; Pitts, Michael; Poole, Lamont; Preusse, Peter; Rapp, Markus; Riese, Martin; Rolf, Christian; Ungermann, Jörn; Voigt, Christiane; Volk, C. Michael; Wirth, Martin; Zahn, Andreas; Ziereis, Helmut (2019) POLSTRACC: Airborne experiment for studying the Polar Stratosphere in a Changing Climate with the high-altitude long-range research aircraft HALO. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. 0</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/bams-d-18-0181.1</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VVWLGJZE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orsolini, Y. J.; Manney, G. L.; Engel, A.; Ovarlez, J.; Claud, C.; Coy, L. (1998) Layering in stratospheric profiles of long-lived trace species: Balloon-borne observations and modeling. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 103</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/97jd03131</link>
      <category>1998</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GCELETRT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ostermöller, J.; Bönisch, H.; Jöckel, P.; Engel, A. (2017) A new time-independent formulation of fractional release. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 2017</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-17-3785-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Y3UMAB6R</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Payan, S.; Camy-Peyret, C.; Oelhaf, H.; Wetzel, G.; Maucher, G.; Keim, C.; Pirre, M.; Huret, N.; Engel, A.; Volk, M. C.; Kuellmann, H.; Kuttippurath, J.; Cortesi, U.; Bianchini, G.; Mencaraglia, F.; Raspollini, P.; Redaelli, G.; Vigouroux, C.; De Maziere, M.; Mikuteit, S.; Blumenstock, T.; Velazco, V.; Notholt, J.; Mahieu, E.; Duchatelet, P.; Smale, D.; Wood, S.; Jones, N.; Piccolo, C.; Payne, V.; Bracher, A.; Glatthor, N.; Stiller, G.; Grunow, K.; Jeseck, P.; Te, Y.; Butz, A. (2009) Validation of version-4.61 methane and nitrous oxide observed by MIPAS. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 9</title>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GL3YNSP9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pfeilsticker, K.; Sturges, W. T.; Bosch, H.; Camy-Peyret, C.; Chipperfield, M. P.; Engel, A.; Fitzenberger, R.; Muller, M.; Payan, S.; Sinnhuber, B. M. (2000) Lower stratospheric organic and inorganic bromine budget for the Arctic winter 1998/99. Geophysical Research Letters. 27</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2000gl011650</link>
      <category>2000</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SUSD66XX</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pierson, J. M.; McKinney, K. A.; Toohey, D. W.; Margitan, J.; Schmidt, U.; Engel, A.; Newman, P. A. (1999) An investigation of C1O photochemistry in the chemically perturbed arctic vortex. Journal of Atmospheric Chemistry. 32</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1023/a:1006136712267</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JV2VJZH8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ploeger, F.; Legras, B.; Charlesworth, E.; Yan, X.; Diallo, M.; Konopka, P.; Birner, T.; Tao, M.; Engel, A.; Riese, M. (2019) How robust are stratospheric age of air trends from different reanalyses?. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-6085-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">CRYUVXS9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapp, Markus; Kaifler, Bernd; Dörnbrack, Andreas; Gisinger, Sonja; Mixa, Tyler; Reichert, Robert; Kaifler, Natalie; Knobloch, Stefanie; Eckert, Ramona; Wildmann, Norman; Giez, Andreas; Krasauskas, Lukas; Preusse, Peter; Geldenhuys, Markus; Riese, Martin; Woiwode, Wolfgang; Friedl-Vallon, Felix; Sinnhuber, Björn-Martin; Torre, Alejandro de la; Alexander, Peter; Hormaechea, Jose Luis; Janches, Diego; Garhammer, Markus; Chau, Jorge L.; Conte, J. Federico; Hoor, Peter; Engel, Andreas (2021) SOUTHTRAC-GW: An Airborne Field Campaign to Explore Gravity Wave Dynamics at the World’s Strongest Hotspot. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society. 102</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/bams-d-20-0034.1</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">B4W5CHKR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pieterse, G.; Krol, M. C.; Batenburg, A. M.; Brenninkmeijer, C. A.; Popa, M. E.; O'Doherty, S.; Grant, A.; Steele, L. P.; Krummel, P. B.; Langenfelds, R. L.; Wang, H. J.; Vermeulen, A. T.; Schmidt, M.; Yver, C.; Jordan, A.; Engel, A.; Fisher, R. E.; Lowry, D.; Nisbet, E. G.; Reimann, S.; Vollmer, M. K.; Steinbacher, M.; Hammer, S.; Forster, G.; Sturges, W. T.; Rockmann, T. (2013) Reassessing the variability in atmospheric H2 using the two-way nested TM5 model. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 118</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/Jgrd.50204</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MLY896FG</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ray, Eric A.; Moore, Fred L.; Rosenlof, Karen H.; Davis, Sean M.; Sweeney, Colm; Tans, Pieter; Wang, Tao; Elkins, James W.; Bönisch, Harald; Engel, Andreas; Sugawara, Satoshi; Nakazawa, T.; Aoki, S. (2014) Improving stratospheric transport trend analysis based on SF₆ and CO₂ measurements. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 119</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2014JD021802</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KYLINM67</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robinson, A. D.; Millard, G. A.; Danis, F.; Guirlet, M.; Harris, N. R. P.; Lee, A. M.; McIntyre, J. D.; Pyle, J. A.; Arvelius, J.; Dagnesjo, S.; Kirkwood, S.; Nilsson, H.; Toohey, D. W.; Deshler, T.; Goutail, F.; Pommereau, J. P.; Elkins, J. W.; Moore, F.; Ray, E.; Schmidt, U.; Engel, A.; Muller, M. (2005) Ozone loss derived from balloon-borne tracer measurements in the 1999/2000 Arctic winter. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 5</title>
      <category>2005</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BCJXUP6S</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schiller, C.; Bauer, R.; Cairo, F.; Deshler, T.; Dornbrack, A.; Elkins, J.; Engel, A.; Flentje, H.; Larsen, N.; I, Levin; Muller, M.; Oltmans, S.; Ovarlez, H.; Ovarlez, J.; Schreiner, J.; Stroh, F.; Voigt, C.; Vomel, H. (2002) Dehydration in the Arctic stratosphere during the SOLVE/THESEO-2000 campaigns. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 107</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/Artn%208293%20Doi%2010.1029/2001jd000463</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MMBXJ5HY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stiller, G. P.; von Clarmann, T.; Haenel, F.; Funke, B.; Glatthor, N.; Grabowski, U.; Kellmann, S.; Kiefer, M.; Linden, A.; Lossow, S.; Lopez-Puertas, M. (2012) Observed temporal evolution of global mean age of stratospheric air for the 2002 to 2010 period. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-12-3311-2012</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LHVHH7FV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rockmann, T.; Brass, M.; Borchers, R.; Engel, A. (2011) The isotopic composition of methane in the stratosphere: high-altitude balloon sample measurements. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-11-13287-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Z8K575PH</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rockmann, T.; Rhee, T. S.; Engel, A. (2003) Heavy hydrogen in the stratosphere. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 3</title>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SFETV4BL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotermund, M. K.; Bense, V.; Chipperfield, M. P.; Engel, A.; Grooß, J. U.; Hoor, P.; Hüneke, T.; Keber, T.; Kluge, F.; Schreiner, B.; Schuck, T.; Vogel, B.; Zahn, A.; Pfeilsticker, K. (2021) Organic and inorganic bromine measurements around the extratropical tropopause and lowermost stratosphere: insights into the transport pathways and total bromine. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-15375-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">S9L9TJSE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rohs, S.; Schiller, C.; Riese, M.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U.; Wetter, T.; Levin, I.; Nakazawa, T.; Aoki, S. (2006) Long-term changes of methane and hydrogen in the stratosphere in the period 1978-2003 and their impact on the abundance of stratospheric water vapor. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 111</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2005jd006877</link>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SKCW7YFJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sala, S.; Boenisch, H.; Keber, T.; Oram, D. E.; Mills, G.; Engel, A. (2014) Deriving an atmospheric budget of total organic bromine using airborne in situ measurements from the western Pacific area during SHIVA. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-14-6903-2014</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AFGBAVIA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scheeren, H. A.; Fischer, H.; Lelieveld, J.; Hoor, P.; Rudolph, J.; Arnold, F.; Bregman, B.; Bruhl, C.; Engel, A.; van der Veen, C.; Brunner, D. (2003) Reactive organic species in the northern extratropical lowermost stratosphere: Seasonal variability and implications for OH. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 108</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2003jd003650</link>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VAADNJ5E</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schiller, C.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U.; Borchers, R.; Ovarlez, J. (1996) The partitioning of hydrogen species in the Arctic winter stratosphere: Implications for microphysical parameters. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 101</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/95jd03765</link>
      <category>1996</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MTW2ZN66</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schneider, B.; Engel, A.; Schlitzer, R. (2004) Effects of depth- and CO2-dependent C : N ratios of particulate organic matter (POM) on the marine carbon cycle. Global Biogeochemical Cycles. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2003gb002184</link>
      <category>2004</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JUV6KCN2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidt, U.; Bauer, R.; Engel, A.; Borchers, R.; Lee, J. (1994) THE VARIATION OF AVAILABLE CHLORINE, CLY, IN THE ARCTIC POLAR VORTEX DURING EASOE. Geophysical Research Letters. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/93gl01055</link>
      <category>1994</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">INPYUD6T</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stachnik, R. A.; Salawitch, R.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U. (1999) Measurements of chlorine partitioning in the winter Arctic stratosphere. Geophysical Research Letters. 26</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/1999gl010817</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EIGPR66H</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strunk, M.; Engel, A.; Schmidt, U.; Volk, C. M.; Wetter, T.; Levin, I.; Glatzel-Mattheier, H. (2000) CO2 and SF6 as stratospheric age tracers: consistency and the effect of mesospheric SF6-loss. Geophysical Research Letters. 27</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/1999gl011044</link>
      <category>2000</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6DP52AB5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sturges, W. T.; Oram, D. E.; Carpenter, L. J.; Penkett, S. A.; Engel, A. (2000) Bromoform as a source of stratospheric bromine. Geophysical Research Letters. 27</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2000gl011444</link>
      <category>2000</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">J2IJXFVK</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stiller, G. P.; von Clarmann, T.; Hoepfner, M.; Glatthor, N.; Grabowski, U.; Kellmann, S.; Kleinert, A.; Linden, A.; Milz, M.; Reddmann, T.; Steck, T.; Fischer, H.; Funke, B.; Lopez-Puertas, M.; Engel, A. (2008) Global distribution of mean age of stratospheric air from MIPAS SF6 measurements. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 8</title>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">V4GGUJP2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sturges, W. T.; Wallington, T. J.; Hurley, M. D.; Shine, K. P.; Sihra, K.; Engel, A.; Oram, D. E.; Penkett, S. A.; Mulvaney, R.; Brenninkmeijer, C. A. M. (2000) A potent greenhouse gas identified in the atmosphere: SF5CF3. Science. 289</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.289.5479.611</link>
      <category>2000</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5CJ5DJHV</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sugita, T.; Kondo, Y.; Nakajima, H.; Schmidt, U.; Engel, A.; Oelhaf, H.; Wetzel, G.; Koike, M.; Newman, P. A. (1998) Denitrification observed inside the Arctic vortex in February 1995. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 103</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/98jd01083</link>
      <category>1998</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ERK7LDKZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tegtmeier, S.; Krüger, K.; Quack, B.; Atlas, E.; Blake, D. R.; Boenisch, H.; Engel, A.; Hepach, H.; Hossaini, R.; Navarro, M. A.; Raimund, S.; Sala, S.; Shi, Q.; Ziska, F. (2013) The contribution of oceanic methyl iodide to stratospheric iodine. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-11869-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7B4U4Y9W</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tilmes, S.; Muller, R.; Engel, A.; Rex, M.; Russell, J. M. (2006) Chemical ozone loss in the Arctic and Antarctic stratosphere between 1992 and 2005. Geophysical Research Letters. 33</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/Artn%20L20812%20Doi%2010.1029/2006gl026925</link>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YNPVSQZR</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wagenhäuser, T.; Engel, A.; Sitals, R. (2021) Testing the altitude attribution and vertical resolution of AirCore measurements with a new spiking method. Atmos. Meas. Tech.. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-14-3923-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JCQE7GEQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tilgner, A.; Schöne, L.; Bräuer, P.; van Pinxteren, D.; Hoffmann, E.; Spindler, G.; Styler, S. A.; Mertes, S.; Birmili, W.; Otto, R.; Merkel, M.; Weinhold, K.; Wiedensohler, A.; Deneke, H.; Schrödner, R.; Wolke, R.; Schneider, J.; Haunold, W.; Engel, A.; Wéber, A.; Herrmann, H. (2014) Comprehensive assessment of meteorological conditions and airflow connectivity during HCCT-2010. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-14-9105-2014</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RMJA9UV9</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vogel, B.; Muller, R.; Engel, A.; Grooss, J. U.; Toohey, D.; Woyke, T.; Stroh, F. (2005) Midlatitude ClO during the maximum atmospheric chlorine burden: in situ balloon measurements and model simulations. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 5</title>
      <category>2005</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7QFTJPHZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wamsley, P. R.; Elkins, J. W.; Fahey, D. W.; Dutton, G. S.; Volk, C. M.; Myers, R. C.; Montzka, S. A.; Butler, J. H.; Clarke, A. D.; Fraser, P. J.; Steele, L. P.; Lucarelli, M. P.; Atlas, E. L.; Schauffler, S. M.; Blake, D. R.; Rowland, F. S.; Sturges, W. T.; Lee, J. M.; Penkett, S. A.; Engel, A.; Stimpfle, R. M.; Chan, K. R.; Weisenstein, D. K.; Ko, M. K. W.; Salawitch, R. J. (1998) Distribution of halon-1211 in the upper troposphere and lower stratosphere and the 1994 total bromine budget. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 103</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/97jd02466</link>
      <category>1998</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">29NG8HLJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wetzel, G.; Oelhaf, H.; Birk, M.; de Lange, A.; Engel, A.; Friedl-Vallon, F.; Kirner, O.; Kleinert, A.; Maucher, G.; Nordmeyer, H.; Orphal, J.; Ruhnke, R.; Sinnhuber, B.-M.; Vogt, P. (2015) Partitioning and budget of inorganic and organic chlorine species observed by MIPAS-B and ℡IS in the Arctic in March 2011. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 15</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-15-8065-2015</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XNR7NE5N</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wetzel, G.; Oelhaf, H.; Kirner, O.; Ruhnke, R.; Friedl-Vallon, F.; Kleinert, A.; Maucher, G.; Fischer, H.; Birk, M.; Wagner, G.; Engel, A. (2010) First remote sensing measurements of ClOOCl along with ClO and ClONO2 in activated and deactivated Arctic vortex conditions using new ClOOCl IR absorption cross sections. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 10</title>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DYG49R5K</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woyke, T.; Muller, R.; Stroh, F.; McKenna, D. S.; Engel, A.; Margitan, J. J.; Rex, M.; Carslaw, K. S. (1999) A test of our understanding of the ozone chemistry in the Arctic polar vortex based on in situ measurements of ClO, BrO, and O-3 in the 1994/1995 winter. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 104</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/1999jd900287</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5FBKEEVN</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zander, R.; Mahieu, E.; Gunson, M. R.; Abrams, M. C.; Chang, A. Y.; Abbas, M.; Aellig, C.; Engel, A.; Goldman, A.; Irion, F. W.; Kampfer, N.; Michelsen, H. A.; Newchurch, M. J.; Rinsland, C. P.; Salawitch, R. J.; Stiller, G. P.; Toon, G. C. (1996) The 1994 northern midlatitude budget of stratospheric chlorine derived from ATMOS/ATLAS-3 observations. Geophysical Research Letters. 23</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/96gl01792</link>
      <category>1996</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">R6XJFXUQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yver, C. E.; Pison, I. C.; Fortems-Cheiney, A.; Schmidt, M.; Chevallier, F.; Ramonet, M.; Jordan, A.; Sovde, O. A.; Engel, A.; Fisher, R. E.; Lowry, D.; Nisbet, E. G.; Levin, I.; Hammer, S.; Necki, J.; Bartyzel, J.; Reimann, S.; Vollmer, M. K.; Steinbacher, M.; Aalto, T.; Maione, M.; Arduini, J.; O'Doherty, S.; Grant, A.; Sturges, W. T.; Forster, G. L.; Lunder, C. R.; Privalov, V.; Paramonova, N.; Werner, A.; Bousquet, P. (2011) A new estimation of the recent tropospheric molecular hydrogen budget using atmospheric observations and variational inversion. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-11-3375-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QV9PP3RT</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoger, M.; Engel, A.; McKenna, D. S.; Schiller, C.; Schmidt, U.; Woyke, T. (1999) Balloon-borne in situ measurements of stratospheric H2O, CH4 and H-2 at midlatitudes. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 104</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/1998jd100024</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7NQLRRRL</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 08:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>