<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AG Schmidli Publikationen (IAU)</title>
    <link>https://www.iau.uni-frankfurt.de</link>
    <description>Publikationen der AG Schmidli, Institut für Atmosphäre und Umwelt (IAU)</description>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Zotero Feed Generator Script (AG Schmidli)</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://184467gianluca.github.io/institut-zotero-feed/AG_Schmidli_zotero_rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Williams, M. Ashok; Hemanth Kumar, A.; Jayachandran, V.; Thakur, Manoj Kumar; Kumar, T. V. Lakshmi (2024) Effect of Wet Scavenging on Black Carbon Aerosols over a Coastal Urban Site in India. Air Quality, Atmosphere &amp; Health</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11869-024-01626-y</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">S5KUWZEC</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wernli, H; Shapiro, \relax MA; Schmidli, J (1999) Upstream Development in Idealized Baroclinic Wave Experiments. ℡LUS SERIES A-DYNAMIC METEOROLOGY AND OCEANOGRAPHY. 51</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1034/j.1600-0870.1999.00003.x</link>
      <category>1999</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5ADY6M7N</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weinkaemmerer, J; Durán, \relax IB; Schmidli, J (2022) The Impact of Large-Scale Winds on Boundary Layer Structure, Thermally Driven Flows, and Exchange Processes over Mountainous Terrain. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 79</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-21-0195.1</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">D3LRUM8F</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weinkaemmerer, J; Durán, \relax IB; Westerhuis, S; Schmidli, J (2022) Stratus over Rolling Terrain: Large-eddy Simulation Reference and Sensitivity to Grid Spacing and Numerics. QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 148</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.4372</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BMJLRBSG</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tian, Y; Duarte, \relax JQ; Schmidli, J (2024) A Station-Based Evaluation of near-Surface South Foehn Evolution in COSMO-1. QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 150</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.4597</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AVNYYTGH</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thomas, \relax ML; Durán, \relax IB; Schmidli, J (2021) Toward Parametrization of Precipitating Shallow Cumulus Cloud Organization via Moisture Variance. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES. 126</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2021JD034939</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YAX5E98U</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sgoff, C; Schomburg, A; Schmidli, J; Potthast, R (2020) Assimilating Synthetic Land Surface Temperature in a Coupled Land-Atmosphere Model. QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 146</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.3883</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">E3JHHGZN</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Westerhuis, S; Fuhrer, O; Bhattacharya, R; Schmidli, J; Bretherton, C (2021) Effects of Terrain-Following Vertical Coordinates on Simulation of Stratus Clouds in Numerical Weather Prediction Models. QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 147</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.3907</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SPKAGM9Y</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weinkaemmerer, J; Göbel, M; Serafin, S; Durán, \relax IB; Schmidli, J (2023) Boundary-Layer Plumes over Mountainous Terrain in Idealized Large-Eddy Simulations. QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 149</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.4551</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5ACME9JZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sprenger, M; Schmidli, J; Egloff, L (2018) The Laseyer Wind Storm - Case Studies and a Climatology. METEOROLOGISCHE ZEITSCHRIFT. 27</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2017/0854</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">L7WDJI9S</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serafin, S; Adler, B; Cuxart, J; De Wekker, \relax SFJ; Gohm, A; Grisogono, B; Kalthoff, N; Kirshbaum, \relax DJ; Rotach, \relax MW; Schmidli, J; Stiperski, I; Vecenaj, Z; Zardi, D (2018) Exchange Processes in the Atmospheric Boundary Layer Over Mountainous Terrain. ATMOSPHERE. 9</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos9030102</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">N33HDA7G</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Böing, S; Fuhrer, O (2018) Accuracy of Simulated Diurnal Valley Winds in the Swiss Alps: Influence of Grid Resolution, Topography Filtering, and Land Surface Datasets. ATMOSPHERE. 9</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos9050196</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7HQV8WKF</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J (2012) The Diabatic Pressure Difference: A New Diagnostic for the Analysis of Valley Winds. MONTHLY WEATHER REVIEW. 140</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-11-00128.1</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GMRPRAWT</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Rotunno, R (2012) Influence of the Valley Surroundings on Valley Wind Dynamics. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 69</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-11-0129.1</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SYLHGHWI</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Billings, B; Chow, \relax FK; de Wekker, \relax SFJ; Doyle, J; Grubisic, V; Holt, T; Jiang, \relax QF; Lundquist, \relax KA; Sheridan, P; Vosper, S; Whiteman, \relax CD; Wyszogrodzki, \relax AA; Zängl, G (2011) Intercomparison of Mesoscale Model Simulations of the Daytime Valley Wind System. MONTHLY WEATHER REVIEW. 139</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2010MWR3523.1</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9QUX5N3P</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Poulos, \relax GS; Daniels, \relax MH; Chow, \relax FK (2009) External Influences on Nocturnal Thermally Driven Flows in a Deep Valley. JOURNAL OF APPLIED METEOROLOGY AND CLIMATOLOGY. 48</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2008JAMC1852.1</link>
      <category>2009</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">IQZFK73H</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Goodess, \relax CM; Frei, C; Haylock, \relax MR; Hundecha, Y; Ribalaygua, J; Schmith, T (2007) Statistical and Dynamical Downscaling of Precipitation: An Evaluation and Comparison of Scenarios for the European Alps. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES. 112</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2005JD007026</link>
      <category>2007</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YYHI6UF2</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Frei, C (2005) Trends of Heavy Precipitation and Wet and Dry Spells in Switzerland during the 20th Century. INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF CLIMATOLOGY. 25</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.1179</link>
      <category>2005</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">34SBL7FZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Rotunno, R (2015) The Quasi-Steady State of the Valley Wind System. FRONTIERS IN EARTH SCIENCE. 3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2015.00079</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PTLSV2U3</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J (2013) Daytime Heat Transfer Processes over Mountainous Terrain. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 70</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-13-083.1</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8LGK2K9E</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Frei, C; Vidale, \relax PL (2006) Downscaling from GC Precipitation: A Benchmark for Dynamical and Statistical Downscaling Methods. INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF CLIMATOLOGY. 26</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.1287</link>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KDT5TNFY</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Schmutz, C; Frei, C; Wanner, H; Schär, C (2002) Mesoscale Precipitation Variability in the Region of the European Alps during the 20th Century. INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF CLIMATOLOGY. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.769</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ANZ4EIW8</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidli, J; Frei, C; Schär, C (2001) Reconstruction of Mesoscale Precipitation Fields from Sparse Observations in Complex Terrain. JOURNAL OF CLIMATE. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/1520-0442(2001)014%3C3289:ROMPFF%3E2.0.CO%3B2</link>
      <category>2001</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">98YEC5Y2</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmidl, J; Rotunno, R (2010) Mechanisms of Along-Valley Winds and Heat Exchange over Mountainous Terrain. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 67</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2010JAS3473.1</link>
      <category>2010</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VXKBX9C4</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schmid, F; Schmidli, J; Hervo, M; Haefele, A (2020) Diurnal Valley Winds in a Deep Alpine Valley: Observations. ATMOSPHERE. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos11010054</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NFPZ86U2</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schlemmer, L; Hohenegger, C; Schmidli, J; Bretherton, \relax CS; Schär, C (2011) An Idealized Cloud-Resolving Framework for the Study of Midlatitude Diurnal Convection over Land. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 68</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2010JAS3640.1</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">72JGJGFA</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quimbayo-Duarte, J; Wagner, J; Wildmann, N; Gerz, T; Schmidli, J (2022) Evaluation of a Forest Parameterization to Improve Boundary Layer Flow Simulations over Complex Terrain. A Case Study Using WRF-LES V4.0.1. GEOSCIENTIFIC MODEL DEVELOPMENT. 15</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-15-5195-2022</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">A6FVS6X4</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schlemmer, L; Hohenegger, C; Schmidli, J; Schär, C (2012) Diurnal Equilibrium Convection and Land Surface-Atmosphere Interactions in an Idealized Cloud-Resolving Model. QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 138</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.1892</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3NJL4I28</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schär, C; Ban, N; Fischer, \relax EM; Rajczak, J; Schmidli, J; Frei, C; Giorgi, F; Karl, \relax TR; Kendon, \relax EJ; Tank, \relax AMGK; O'Gorman, \relax PA; Sillmann, J; Zhang, \relax XB; Zwiers, \relax FW (2016) Percentile Indices for Assessing Changes in Heavy Precipitation Events. CLIMATIC CHANGE. 137</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10584-016-1669-2</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">48SEC48Q</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotach, \relax MW; Serafin, S; Ward, \relax HC; Arpagaus, M; Colfescu, I; Cuxart, J; De Wekker, \relax SFJ; Grubisic, V; Kalthoff, N; Karl, T; Kirshbaum, \relax DJ; Lehner, M; Mobbs, S; Paci, A; Palazzi, E; Bailey, A; Schmidli, J; Wittmann, C; Wohlfahrt, G; Zardi, D (2022) A Collaborative Effort to Better Understand, Measure, and Model Atmospheric Exchange Processes over Mountains. BULLETIN OF THE AMERICAN METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 103</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-21-0232.1</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GNLVCIG3</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reilly, S; Durán, \relax IB; Jacob, \relax AT; Schmidli, J (2022) An Evaluation of Algebraic Turbulence Length Scale Formulations. ATMOSPHERE. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos13040605</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NXHMN9HD</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panosetti, D; Böing, S; Schlemmer, L; Schmidli, J (2016) Idealized Large-Eddy and Convection-Resolving Simulations of Moist Convection over Mountainous Terrain. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 73</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-15-0341.1</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9PKZTGC3</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mašek, Ján; Ďurán, Ivan Bašták; Brožková, Radmila (2022) Stable Numerical Implementation of a Turbulence Scheme with Two Prognostic Turbulence Energies. Monthly Weather Review. 150</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-21-0172.1</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LE63CT42</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>März, Benedikt; Fundel, Vanessa; Kalinka, Frank; Schultze, Markus; Schmidli, Jürg (2023) Development of an Ensemble-Based Forecasting Tool of Hazardous Icing Conditions for German Transmission System Operators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2023-01-1438</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YAHBXKE3</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lyon, \relax SW; Dominguez, F; Gochis, \relax DJ; Brunsell, \relax NA; Castro, \relax CL; Chow, \relax FK; Fan, Y; Fuka, D; Hong, Y; Kucera, \relax PA; Nesbitt, \relax SW; Salzmann, N; Schmidli, J; Snyder, \relax PK; Teuling, \relax AJ; Twine, \relax TE; Levis, S; Lundquist, \relax JD; Salvucci, \relax GD; Sealy, \relax AM; Walter, \relax MT (2008) Coupling Terrestrial and Atmospheric Water Dynamics to Improve Prediction in a Changing Environment. BULLETIN OF THE AMERICAN METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 89</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2008BAMS2547.1</link>
      <category>2008</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">W5VMT5XK</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keller, M; Kröner, N; Fuhrer, O; Lüthi, D; Schmidli, J; Stengel, M; Stöckli, R; Schär, C (2018) The Sensitivity of Alpine Summer Convection to Surrogate Climate Change: An Intercomparison between Convection-Parameterizing and Convection-Resolving Models. ATMOSPHERIC CHEMISTRY AND PHYSICS. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-5253-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">X2ST9MWE</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keller, M; Fuhrer, O; Schmidli, J; Stengel, M; Stöckli, R; Schär, C (2016) Evaluation of Convection-Resolving Models Using Satellite Data: The Diurnal Cycle of Summer Convection over the Alps. METEOROLOGISCHE ZEITSCHRIFT. 25</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2015/0715</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">V6TLXZ87</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prein, \relax AF; Langhans, W; Fosser, G; Ferrone, A; Ban, N; Goergen, K; Keller, M; Tölle, M; Gutjahr, O; Feser, F; Brisson, E; Kollet, S; Schmidli, J; van Lipzig, \relax NPM; Leung, R (2015) A Review on Regional Convection-Permitting Climate Modeling: Demonstrations, Prospects, and Challenges. REVIEWS OF GEOPHYSICS. 53</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2014RG000475</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NAATYFGE</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Langhans, W; Schmidli, J; Fuhrer, O; Bieri, S; Schär, C (2013) Long-Term Simulations of Thermally Driven Flows and Orographic Convection at Convection-Parameterizing and Cloud-Resolving Resolutions. JOURNAL OF APPLIED METEOROLOGY AND CLIMATOLOGY. 52</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-12-0167.1</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">98N8CRTI</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Langhans, W; Schmidli, J; Schär, C (2012) Mesoscale Impacts of Explicit Numerical Diffusion in a Convection-Permitting Model. MONTHLY WEATHER REVIEW. 140</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/2011MWR3650.1</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NHYVKKHL</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Langhans, W; Schmidli, J; Schär, C (2012) Bulk Convergence of Cloud-Resolving Simulations of Moist Convection over Complex Terrain. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 69</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-11-0252.1</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XX8ZN5A6</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hohenegger, C; Ament, F; Beyrich, F; Löhnert, U; Rust, H; Bange, J; Boeck, T; Böttcher, C; Boventer, J; Burgemeister, F; Clemens, M; Detring, C; Detring, I; Dewani, N; Duran, \relax IB; Fiedler, S; Göber, M; van Heerwaarden, C; Heusinkveld, B; Kirsch, B; Klocke, D; Knist, C; Lange, I; Lauermann, F; Lehmann, V; Lehmke, J; Leinweber, R; Lundgren, K; Masbou, M; Mauder, M; Mol, W; Nevermann, H; Nomokonova, T; Päschke, E; Platis, A; Reichardt, J; Rochette, L; Sakradzija, M; Schlemmer, L; Schmidli, J; Shokri, N; Sobottke, V; Speidel, J; Steinheuer, J; Turner, \relax DD; Vogelmann, H; Wedemeyer, C; Weide-Luiz, E; Wiesner, S; Wildmann, N; Wolz, K; Wetz, T (2023) FESSTVaL The Field Experiment on Submesoscale Spatio-Temporal Variability in Lindenberg. BULLETIN OF THE AMERICAN METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 104</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-21-0330.1</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">CWA7E4CA</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Froidevaux, P; Schlemmer, L; Schmidli, J; Langhans, W; Schär, C (2014) Influence of the Background Wind on the Local Soil Moisture-Precipitation Feedback. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 71</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-13-0180.1</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">WRMM4Z59</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frei, C; Schöll, R; Fukutome, S; Schmidli, J; Vidale, \relax PL (2006) Future Change of Precipitation Extremes in Europe:: Intercomparison of Scenarios from Regional Climate Models. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES. 111</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2005JD005965</link>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3BJG7793</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Durán, \relax IB; Sakradzija, M; Schmidli, J (2022) The Two-Energies Turbulence Scheme Coupled to the Assumed PDF Method. JOURNAL OF ADVANCES IN MODELING EARTH SYSTEMS. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2021MS002922</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">VFZ2MQQ9</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Durán, \relax IB; Geleyn, \relax JF; Vána, F; Schmidli, J; Brozková, R (2018) A Turbulence Scheme with Two Prognostic Turbulence Energies. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 75</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-18-0026.1</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YGBUCX36</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hohenegger, C; Ament, F; Beyrich, F; Löhnert, U; Rust, H; Bange, J; Böck, T; Böttcher, C; Boventer, J; Burgemeister, F; Clemens, M; Detring, C; Detring, I; Dewani, N; Duran, \relax IB; Fiedler, S; Göber, M; van Heerwaarden, C; Heusinkveld, B; Kirsch, B; Klocke, D; Knist, C; Lange, I; Lauermann, F; Lehmann, V; Lehmke, J; Leinweber, R; Lundgren, K; Masbou, M; Mauder, M; Mol, W; Nevermann, H; Nomokonova, T; Päschke, E; Platis, A; Reichardt, J; Rochette, L; Sakradzija, M; Schlemmer, L; Schmidli, J; Shokri, N; Sobottke, V; Speidel, J; Steinheuer, J; Turner, \relax DD; Vogelmann, H; Wedemeyer, C; Weide-Luiz, E; Wiesner, S; Wildmann, N; Wolz, K; Wetz, T (2023) The Field Experiment on Submesoscale Spatio-Temporal Variability in Lindenberg. BULLETIN OF THE AMERICAN METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 104</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-21-0330.1</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3I3GRY9A</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hassanzadeh, H; Schmidli, J; Langhans, W; Schlemmer, L; Schär, C (2016) Impact of Topography on the Diurnal Cycle of Summertime Moist Convection in Idealized Simulations. METEOROLOGISCHE ZEITSCHRIFT. 25</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/metz/2015/0653</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">R9E4L7LK</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efthymiadis, D; Jones, \relax PD; Briffa, \relax KR; Auer, I; Böhm, R; Schöner, W; Frei, C; Schmidli, J (2006) Construction of a 10-Min-Gridded Precipitation Data Set for the Greater Alpine Region for 1800-2003 -: Art. No. D01105. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES. 111</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2005JD006120</link>
      <category>2006</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5U9LVDDZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Durán, \relax IB; Köhler, M; Eichhorn-Muller, A; Maurer, V; Schmidli, J; Schomburg, A; Klocke, D; Göcke, T; Schäfer, S; Schlemmer, L; Dewani, N (2021) The ICON Single-Column Mode. ATMOSPHERE. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos12070906</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MNUGYURZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Durán, \relax IB; Schmidli, J; Bhattacharya, R (2020) A Budget-Based Turbulence Length Scale Diagnostic. ATMOSPHERE. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos11040425</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9CWQRPY8</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benoit, R; Schär, C; Binder, P; Chamberland, S; Davies, \relax HC; Desgagné, M; Girard, C; Keil, C; Kouwen, N; Lüthi, D; Maric, D; Muller, E; Pellerin, P; Schmidli, J; Schubiger, F; Schwierz, C; Sprenger, M; Walser, A; Willemse, S; Yu, W; Zala, E (2002) The Real-Time Ultrafinescale Forecast Support during the Special Observing Period of the MAP. BULLETIN OF THE AMERICAN METEOROLOGICAL SOCIETY. 83</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/1520-0477(2002)083%3C0085:TRTUFS%3E2.3.CO%3B2</link>
      <category>2002</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">99H5E7HB</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bannon, \relax PR; Schmidli, J; Schär, C (2003) On Potential Vorticity Flux Vectors. JOURNAL OF THE ATMOSPHERIC SCIENCES. 60</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1175/1520-0469(2003)060%3C2917:OPVFV%3E2.0.CO%3B2</link>
      <category>2003</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LY9LL2NC</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ban, N; Schmidli, J; Schär, C (2015) Heavy Precipitation in a Changing Climate: Does Short-Term Summer Precipitation Increase Faster?. GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH LETTERS. 42</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2014GL062588</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">N9Q3BQFB</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ban, N; Schmidli, J; Schär, C (2014) Evaluation of the Convection-Resolving Regional Climate Modeling Approach in Decade-Long Simulations. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES. 119</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2014JD021478</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2925CAW5</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anurose, \relax TJ; Durán, \relax IB; Schmidli, J; Seifert, A (2020) Understanding the Moisture Variance in Precipitating Shallow Cumulus Convection. JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES. 125</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD031178</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EZAETC4M</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dewani, N; Sakradzija, M; Schlemmer, L; Leinweber, R; Schmidli, J (2023) Dependency of Vertical Velocity Variance on Meteorological Conditions in the Convective Boundary Layer. ATMOSPHERIC CHEMISTRY AND PHYSICS. 23</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-4045-2023</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">KUEEP4KV</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boutle, I; Angevine, W; Bao, \relax JW; Bergot, T; Bhattacharya, R; Bott, A; Ducongé, L; Forbes, R; Goecke, T; Grell, E; Hill, A; Igel, \relax AL; Kudzotsa, I; Lac, C; Maronga, B; Romakkaniemi, S; Schmidli, J; Schwenkel, J; Steeneveld, \relax GJ; Vié, B (2022) Demistify: A Large-Eddy Simulation (LES) and Single-Column Model (SCM) Intercomparison of Radiation Fog. ATMOSPHERIC CHEMISTRY AND PHYSICS. 22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-319-2022</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RN2R78U6</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bašták Ďurán, Ivan; Marquet, Pascal (2021) Les travaux sur la turbulence : les origines, Toucans, Cost-ES0905 et influence de l'entropie. La Météorologie</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37053/lameteorologie-2021-0023</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">J76HSALJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ban, \relax NI; Rajczak, J; Schmidli, J; Scher, C (2020) Analysis of Alpine Precipitation Extremes Using Generalized Extreme Value Theory in Convection-Resolving Climate Simulations. CLIMATE DYNAMICS. 55</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-018-4339-4</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">E2XRRBKE</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alladi, Hemanth Kumar; Satheesh Chandran, P.R.; M, Venkat Ratnam (2024) Impact of ENSO on the UTLS Chemical Composition in the Asian Summer Monsoon Anticyclone. Atmospheric Research. 309</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2024.107551</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DZJ5RHEJ</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 08:11:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>