<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AG Vogel Publikationen (IAU)</title>
    <link>https://www.iau.uni-frankfurt.de</link>
    <description>Publikationen der AG Vogel, Institut für Atmosphäre und Umwelt (IAU)</description>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Zotero Feed Generator Script (AG Vogel)</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://184467gianluca.github.io/institut-zotero-feed/AG_Vogel_zotero_rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoma, Markus; Bachmeier, Franziska; Knauf, Karina; David, Julia; Simon, Mario; Vogel, Alexander L. (2025) Seasonal analysis of organic aerosol composition resolves anthropogenic and biogenic sources at a rural background station in central Europe. Environ. Sci.: Atmos.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/D4EA00163J</link>
      <category>2025</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35NHR6XZ</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ma, Jialiang; Reininger, Natalie; Zhao, Cunliang; Döbler, Damian; Rüdiger, Julian; Qiu, Yanting; Ungeheuer, Florian; Simon, Mario; D’Angelo, Luca; Breuninger, Anna; David, Julia; Bai, Yanxin; Li, Yushan; Xue, Ying; Li, Lili; Wang, Yuchen; Hildmann, Stefanie; Hoffmann, Thorsten; Liu, Bangjun; Niu, Hongya; Wu, Zhijun; Vogel, Alexander L. (2025) Unveiling a large fraction of hidden organosulfates in ambient organic aerosol. Nat Commun. 16</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59420-y</link>
      <category>2025</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ESSBDH2R</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burgay, François; Salionov, Daniil; Singer, Thomas; Eichler, Anja; Brütsch, Sabina; Jenk, Theo M.; Vogel, Alexander L.; Papina, Tatyana; Bjelić, Saša; Schwikowski, Margit (2025) Nontarget screening of a Siberian ice core reveals changes in the pre-industrial to industrial organic aerosol composition. Sci. Adv.. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr1923</link>
      <category>2025</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">53JCI6PV</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tang, Rongzhi; Ma, Jialiang; Zhang, Ruifeng; Cui, Weizhen; Qin, Yuanyuan; Chu, Yangxi; Qin, Yiming; Vogel, Alexander L.; Chan, Chak K. (2025) Enhanced sulfate formation in mixed biomass burning and sea-salt interactions mediated by photosensitization: effects of chloride, nitrogen-containing compounds, and atmospheric aging. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 25</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-425-2025</link>
      <category>2025</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">I6M3FQEU</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Borchers, Christine; Seymore, Jackson; Gautam, Martanda; Dörholt, Konstantin; Müller, Yannik; Arndt, Andreas; Gömmer, Laura; Ungeheuer, Florian; Szakáll, Miklós; Borrmann, Stephan; Theis, Alexander; Vogel, Alexander L.; Hoffmann, Thorsten (2024) Retention of α -pinene oxidation products and nitro-aromatic compounds during riming. Atmos. Chem. Phys.. 24</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-13961-2024</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AE6KWZ7C</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decker, Zachary C. J.; Alpert, Peter A.; Ammann, Markus; Anet, Julien G.; Bauer, Michael; Cui, Tianqu; Durdina, Lukas; Edebeli, Jacinta; Gysel-Beer, Martin; Prévôt, Andre S. H.; Qi, Lu; Slowik, Jay G.; Spirig, Curdin; Tinorua, Sarah; Ungeheuer, Florian; Vogel, Alexander; Zhang, Jun; Brem, Benjamin T. (2024) Emission and Formation of Aircraft Engine Oil Ultrafine Particles. ACS EST Air. 1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestair.4c00184</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">H849W4Z5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daellenbach, Kaspar R.; Cai, Jing; Hakala, Simo; Dada, Lubna; Yan, Chao; Du, Wei; Yao, Lei; Zheng, Feixue; Ma, Jialiang; Ungeheuer, Florian; Vogel, Alexander L.; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Hao, Yufang; Liu, Yongchun; Bianchi, Federico; Uzu, Gaëlle; Jaffrezo, Jean-Luc; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Donahue, Neil M.; Kulmala, Markku (2024) Substantial contribution of transported emissions to organic aerosol in Beijing. Nat. Geosci.. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01493-3</link>
      <category>2024</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JLBIHII5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Williams, J.; Crowley, J.; Fischer, H.; Harder, H.; Martinez, M.; Petäjä, T.; Rinne, J.; Bäck, J.; Boy, M.; Dal Maso, M.; Hakala, J.; Kajos, M.; Keronen, P.; Rantala, P.; Aalto, J.; Aaltonen, H.; Paatero, J.; Vesala, T.; Hakola, H.; Levula, J.; Pohja, T.; Herrmann, F.; Auld, J.; Mesarchaki, E.; Song, W.; Yassaa, N.; Nölscher, A.; Johnson, A. M.; Custer, T.; Sinha, V.; Thieser, J.; Pouvesle, N.; Taraborrelli, D.; Tang, M. J.; Bozem, H.; Hosaynali-Beygi, Z.; Axinte, R.; Oswald, R.; Novelli, A.; Kubistin, D.; Hens, K.; Javed, U.; Trawny, K.; Breitenberger, C.; Hidalgo, P. J.; Ebben, C. J.; Geiger, F. M.; Corrigan, A. L.; Russell, L. M.; Ouwersloot, H. G.; Vilà-Guerau de Arellano, J.; Ganzeveld, L.; Vogel, A.; Beck, M.; Bayerle, A.; Kampf, C. J.; Bertelmann, M.; Köllner, F.; Hoffmann, T.; Valverde, J.; González, D.; Riekkola, M.-L.; Kulmala, M.; Lelieveld, J. (2011) The summertime Boreal forest field measurement intensive (HUMPPA-COPEC-2010): an overview of meteorological and chemical influences. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 11</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-11-10599-2011</link>
      <category>2011</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6YGLSHW9</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dada, Lubna; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Simon, Mario; Fischer, Lukas; Heinritzi, Martin; Wang, Mingyi; Xiao, Mao; Vogel, Alexander L.; Ahonen, Lauri; Amorim, Antonio; Baalbaki, Rima; Baccarini, Andrea; Baltensperger, Urs; Bianchi, Federico; Daellenbach, Kaspar R.; DeVivo, Jenna; Dias, Antonio; Dommen, Josef; Duplissy, Jonathan; Finkenzeller, Henning; Hansel, Armin; He, Xu-Cheng; Hofbauer, Victoria; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Kangasluoma, Juha; Kim, Changhyuk; Kürten, Andreas; Kvashnin, Aleksander; Mauldin, Roy; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Marten, Ruby; Mentler, Bernhard; Nie, Wei; Petäjä, Tuukka; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Saathoff, Harald; Tauber, Christian; Tome, Antonio; Molteni, Ugo; Volkamer, Rainer; Wagner, Robert; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wimmer, Daniela; Winkler, Paul M.; Yan, Chao; Zha, Qiaozhi; Rissanen, Matti; Gordon, Hamish; Curtius, Joachim; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Donahue, Neil M.; Kirkby, Jasper; El Haddad, Imad; Kulmala, Markku (2023) Role of sesquiterpenes in biogenic new particle formation. Science advances. 9</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adi5297</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">WE34M9JT</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burgay, François; Salionov, Daniil; Huber, Carla Jennifer; Singer, Thomas; Eichler, Anja; Ungeheuer, Florian; Vogel, Alexander; Schwikowski, Margit; Bjelić, Saša (2023) Hybrid Targeted/Untargeted Screening Method for the Determination of Wildfire and Water-Soluble Organic Tracers in Ice Cores and Snow. Analytical chemistry. 95</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.3c01852</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2Q7UC9UR</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nie, Wei; Yan, Chao; Yang, Liwen; Roldin, Pontus; Liu, Yuliang; Vogel, Alexander L.; Molteni, Ugo; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Finkenzeller, Henning; Amorim, Antonio; Bianchi, Federico; Curtius, Joachim; Dada, Lubna; Draper, Danielle C.; Duplissy, Jonathan; Hansel, Armin; He, Xu-Cheng; Hofbauer, Victoria; Jokinen, Tuija; Kim, Changhyuk; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Nichman, Leonid; Mauldin, Roy L.; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Mentler, Bernhard; Mizelli-Ojdanic, Andrea; Petäjä, Tuukka; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Schallhart, Simon; Simon, Mario; Tauber, Christian; Tomé, António; Volkamer, Rainer; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wagner, Robert; Wang, Mingyi; Ye, Penglin; Li, Haiyan; Huang, Wei; Qi, Ximeng; Lou, Sijia; Liu, Tengyu; Chi, Xuguang; Dommen, Josef; Baltensperger, Urs; El Haddad, Imad; Kirkby, Jasper; Worsnop, Douglas; Kulmala, Markku; Donahue, Neil M.; Ehn, Mikael; Ding, Aijun (2023) NO at low concentration can enhance the formation of highly oxygenated biogenic molecules in the atmosphere. Nature communications. 14</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-39066-4</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">DT6YPFAW</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tang, Rongzhi; Zhang, Ruifeng; Ma, Jialiang; Song, Kai; Mabato, Beatrix Rosette Go; Cuevas, Rosemarie Ann Infante; Zhou, Liyuan; Liang, Zhancong; Vogel, Alexander L.; Guo, Song; Chan, Chak K. (2023) Sulfate Formation by Photosensitization in Mixed Incense Burning-Sodium Chloride Particles: Effects of RH, Light Intensity, and Aerosol Aging. Environmental science &amp; technology. 57</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c02225</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">T7TRS8DL</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caudillo, Lucía; Surdu, Mihnea; Lopez, Brandon; Wang, Mingyi; Thoma, Markus; Bräkling, Steffen; Buchholz, Angela; Simon, Mario; Wagner, Andrea C.; Müller, Tatjana; Granzin, Manuel; Heinritzi, Martin; Amorim, Antonio; Bell, David M.; Brasseur, Zoé; Dada, Lubna; Duplissy, Jonathan; Finkenzeller, Henning; He, Xu-Cheng; Lamkaddam, Houssni; Mahfouz, Naser G. A.; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Manninen, Hanna E.; Marie, Guillaume; Marten, Ruby; Mauldin, Roy L.; Mentler, Bernhard; Onnela, Antti; Petäjä, Tuukka; Pfeifer, Joschka; Philippov, Maxim; Piedehierro, Ana A.; Rörup, Birte; Scholz, Wiebke; Shen, Jiali; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Tauber, Christian; Tian, Ping; Tomé, António; Umo, Nsikanabasi Silas; Wang, Dongyu S.; Wang, Yonghong; Weber, Stefan K.; Welti, André; Zauner-Wieczorek, Marcel; Baltensperger, Urs; Flagan, Richard C.; Hansel, Armin; Kirkby, Jasper; Kulmala, Markku; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Haddad, Imad El; Donahue, Neil M.; Vogel, Alexander L.; Kürten, Andreas; Curtius, Joachim (2023) An intercomparison study of four different techniques for measuring the chemical composition of nanoparticles. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 23</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-23-6613-2023</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">V5F9BWU5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muñoz-Vega, Edinsson; Schulz, Stephan; Rodriguez-Escales, Paula; Behle, Vera; Spada, Lucas; Vogel, Alexander L.; Sanchez-Vila, Xavier; Schüth, Christoph (2023) Role of Soil Biofilms in Clogging and Fate of Pharmaceuticals: A Laboratory-Scale Column Experiment. Environmental science &amp; technology. 57</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c02034</link>
      <category>2023</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ABYTK7L6</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ma, Jialiang; Ungeheuer, Florian; Zheng, Feixue; Du, Wei; Wang, Yonghong; Cai, Jing; Zhou, Ying; Yan, Chao; Liu, Yongchun; Kulmala, Markku; Daellenbach, Kaspar R.; Vogel, Alexander L. (2022) Nontarget Screening Exhibits a Seasonal Cycle of PM2.5 Organic Aerosol Composition in Beijing. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 56</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.1c06905</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">HJNMWMIS</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karges, Ursula; de Boer, Sabrina; Vogel, Alexander L.; Püttmann, Wilhelm (2022) Implementation of initial emission mitigation measures for 1,4-dioxane in Germany: Are they taking effect?. Science of The Total Environment. 806</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.150701</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">E7DL7VI3</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wallraff, Jonas P.; Ungeheuer, Florian; Dombrowski, Andrea; Oehlmann, Jörg; Vogel, Alexander L. (2022) Occurrence and in vitro toxicity of organic compounds in urban background PM2.5. Science of The Total Environment. 817</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.152779</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6HM6NG66</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ungeheuer, Florian; Caudillo, Lucía; Ditas, Florian; Simon, Mario; van Pinxteren, Dominik; Kılıç, Doğuşhan; Rose, Diana; Jacobi, Stefan; Kürten, Andreas; Curtius, Joachim; Vogel, Alexander L. (2022) Nucleation of jet engine oil vapours is a large source of aviation-related ultrafine particles. Communications Earth &amp; Environment. 3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43247-022-00653-w</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6296XI9Z</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoma, Markus; Bachmeier, Franziska; Gottwald, Felix Leonard; Simon, Mario; Vogel, Alexander Lucas (2022) Mass spectrometry-based Aerosolomics: a new approach to resolve sources, composition, and partitioning of secondary organic aerosol. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques. 15</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-15-7137-2022</link>
      <category>2022</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2TU9V7I8</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ungeheuer, Florian; van Pinxteren, Dominik; Vogel, Alexander L. (2021) Identification and source attribution of organic compounds in ultrafine particles near Frankfurt International Airport. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 21</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-21-3763-2021</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SLMIA27K</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tomaz, Sophie; Wang, Dongyu; Zabalegui, Nicolás; Li, Dandan; Lamkaddam, Houssni; Bachmeier, Franziska; Vogel, Alexander; Monge, María Eugenia; Perrier, Sébastien; Baltensperger, Urs; George, Christian; Rissanen, Matti; Ehn, Mikael; El Haddad, Imad; Riva, Matthieu (2021) Structures and reactivity of peroxy radicals and dimeric products revealed by online tandem mass spectrometry. Nature communications. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-20532-2</link>
      <category>2021</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">55Z6GPHI</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heinritzi, Martin; Dada, Lubna; Simon, Mario; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Wagner, Andrea C.; Fischer, Lukas; Ahonen, Lauri R.; Amanatidis, Stavros; Baalbaki, Rima; Baccarini, Andrea; Bauer, Paulus S.; Baumgartner, Bernhard; Bianchi, Federico; Brilke, Sophia; Chen, Dexian; Chiu, Randall; Dias, Antonio; Dommen, Josef; Duplissy, Jonathan; Finkenzeller, Henning; Frege, Carla; Fuchs, Claudia; Garmash, Olga; Gordon, Hamish; Granzin, Manuel; El Haddad, Imad; He, Xucheng; Helm, Johanna; Hofbauer, Victoria; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Kangasluoma, Juha; Keber, Timo; Kim, Changhyuk; Kürten, Andreas; Lamkaddam, Houssni; Laurila, Tiia M.; Lampilahti, Janne; Lee, Chuan Ping; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Leiminger, Markus; Mai, Huajun; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Manninen, Hanna Elina; Marten, Ruby; Mathot, Serge; Mauldin, Roy Lee; Mentler, Bernhard; Molteni, Ugo; Müller, Tatjana; Nie, Wei; Nieminen, Tuomo; Onnela, Antti; Partoll, Eva; Passananti, Monica; Petäjä, Tuukka; Pfeifer, Joschka; Pospisilova, Veronika; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Rissanen, Matti P.; Rose, Clémence; Schobesberger, Siegfried; Scholz, Wiebke; Scholze, Kay; Sipilä, Mikko; Steiner, Gerhard; Stozhkov, Yuri; Tauber, Christian; Tham, Yee Jun; Vazquez-Pufleau, Miguel; Virtanen, Annele; Vogel, Alexander L.; Volkamer, Rainer; Wagner, Robert; Wang, Mingyi; Weitz, Lena; Wimmer, Daniela; Xiao, Mao; Yan, Chao; Ye, Penglin; Zha, Qiaozhi; Zhou, Xueqin; Amorim, Antonio; Baltensperger, Urs; Hansel, Armin; Kulmala, Markku; Tomé, António; Winkler, Paul M.; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Donahue, Neil M.; Kirkby, Jasper; Curtius, Joachim (2020) Molecular understanding of the suppression of new-particle formation by isoprene. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-11809-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">K7WPRBUC</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qi, Lu; Vogel, Alexander L.; Esmaeilirad, Sepideh; Cao, Liming; Zheng, Jing; Jaffrezo, Jean-Luc; Fermo, Paola; Kasper-Giebl, Anne; Daellenbach, Kaspar R.; Chen, Mindong; Ge, Xinlei; Baltensperger, Urs; Prévôt, André S. H.; Slowik, Jay G. (2020) A 1-year characterization of organic aerosol composition and sources using an extractive electrospray ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometer (EESI-TOF) Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-7875-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GVWBCA45</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yan, C.; Nie, W.; Vogel, A. L.; Dada, L.; Lehtipalo, K.; Stolzenburg, D.; Wagner, R.; Rissanen, M. P.; Xiao, M.; Ahonen, L.; Fischer, L.; Rose, C.; Bianchi, F.; Gordon, H.; Simon, M.; Heinritzi, M.; Garmash, O.; Roldin, P.; Dias, A.; Ye, P.; Hofbauer, V.; Amorim, A.; Bauer, P. S.; Bergen, A.; Bernhammer, A-K; Breitenlechner, M.; Brilke, S.; Buchholz, A.; Mazon, S. Buenrostro; Canagaratna, M. R.; Chen, X.; Ding, A.; Dommen, J.; Draper, D. C.; Duplissy, J.; Frege, C.; Heyn, C.; Guida, R.; Hakala, J.; Heikkinen, L.; Hoyle, C. R.; Jokinen, T.; Kangasluoma, J.; Kirkby, J.; Kontkanen, J.; Kürten, A.; Lawler, M. J.; Mai, H.; Mathot, S.; Mauldin, R. L.; Molteni, U.; Nichman, L.; Nieminen, T.; Nowak, J.; Ojdanic, A.; Onnela, A.; Pajunoja, A.; Petäjä, T.; Piel, F.; Quéléver, L. L. J.; Sarnela, N.; Schallhart, S.; Sengupta, K.; Sipilä, M.; Tomé, A.; Tröstl, J.; Väisänen, O.; Wagner, A. C.; Ylisirniö, A.; Zha, Q.; Baltensperger, U.; Carslaw, K. S.; Curtius, J.; Flagan, R. C.; Hansel, A.; Riipinen, I.; Smith, J. N.; Virtanen, A.; Winkler, P. M.; Donahue, N. M.; Kerminen, V-M; Kulmala, M.; Ehn, M.; Worsnop, D. R. (2020) Size-dependent influence of NOx on the growth rates of organic aerosol particles. Science advances. 6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aay4945</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JQ6HUHWS</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simon, Mario; Dada, Lubna; Heinritzi, Martin; Scholz, Wiebke; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Fischer, Lukas; Wagner, Andrea C.; Kürten, Andreas; Rörup, Birte; He, Xu-Cheng; Almeida, João; Baalbaki, Rima; Baccarini, Andrea; Bauer, Paulus S.; Beck, Lisa; Bergen, Anton; Bianchi, Federico; Bräkling, Steffen; Brilke, Sophia; Caudillo, Lucia; Chen, Dexian; Chu, Biwu; Dias, António; Draper, Danielle C.; Duplissy, Jonathan; El-Haddad, Imad; Finkenzeller, Henning; Frege, Carla; Gonzalez-Carracedo, Loic; Gordon, Hamish; Granzin, Manuel; Hakala, Jani; Hofbauer, Victoria; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Kim, Changhyuk; Kong, Weimeng; Lamkaddam, Houssni; Lee, Chuan P.; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Leiminger, Markus; Mai, Huajun; Manninen, Hanna E.; Marie, Guillaume; Marten, Ruby; Mentler, Bernhard; Molteni, Ugo; Nichman, Leonid; Nie, Wei; Ojdanic, Andrea; Onnela, Antti; Partoll, Eva; Petäjä, Tuukka; Pfeifer, Joschka; Philippov, Maxim; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Ranjithkumar, Ananth; Rissanen, Matti P.; Schallhart, Simon; Schobesberger, Siegfried; Schuchmann, Simone; Shen, Jiali; Sipilä, Mikko; Steiner, Gerhard; Stozhkov, Yuri; Tauber, Christian; Tham, Yee J.; Tomé, António R.; Vazquez-Pufleau, Miguel; Vogel, Alexander L.; Wagner, Robert; Wang, Mingyi; Wang, Dongyu S.; Wang, Yonghong; Weber, Stefan K.; Wu, Yusheng; Xiao, Mao; Yan, Chao; Ye, Penglin; Ye, Qing; Zauner-Wieczorek, Marcel; Zhou, Xueqin; Baltensperger, Urs; Dommen, Josef; Flagan, Richard C.; Hansel, Armin; Kulmala, Markku; Volkamer, Rainer; Winkler, Paul M.; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Donahue, Neil M.; Kirkby, Jasper; Curtius, Joachim (2020) Molecular understanding of new-particle formation from \textgreeka-pinene between -50 and +25 °C. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-9183-2020</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">JQD7I2SG</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wang, Mingyi; Chen, Dexian; Xiao, Mao; Ye, Qing; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Hofbauer, Victoria; Ye, Penglin; Vogel, Alexander L.; Mauldin, Roy L.; Amorim, Antonio; Baccarini, Andrea; Baumgartner, Bernhard; Brilke, Sophia; Dada, Lubna; Dias, António; Duplissy, Jonathan; Finkenzeller, Henning; Garmash, Olga; He, Xu-Cheng; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Kim, Changhyuk; Kvashnin, Alexander; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Fischer, Lukas; Molteni, Ugo; Petäjä, Tuukka; Pospisilova, Veronika; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Rissanen, Matti; Simon, Mario; Tauber, Christian; Tomé, António; Wagner, Andrea C.; Weitz, Lena; Volkamer, Rainer; Winkler, Paul M.; Kirkby, Jasper; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Kulmala, Markku; Baltensperger, Urs; Dommen, Josef; El-Haddad, Imad; Donahue, Neil M. (2020) Photo-oxidation of Aromatic Hydrocarbons Produces Low-Volatility Organic Compounds. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 54</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.0c02100</link>
      <category>2020</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LN5MNRGW</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hartmann, M.; Blunier, T.; Brügger, S. O.; Schmale, J.; Schwikowski, M.; Vogel, A.; Wex, H.; Stratmann, F. (2019) Variation of Ice Nucleating Particles in the European Arctic Over the Last Centuries. Geophysical Research Letters. 46</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2019GL082311</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PI3L2KPA</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daellenbach, K. R.; Kourtchev, I.; Vogel, A. L.; Bruns, E. A.; Jiang, J.; Petäjä, T.; Jaffrezo, J.-L.; Aksoyoglu, S.; Kalberer, M.; Baltensperger, U.; El Haddad, I.; Prévôt, A. S. H. (2019) Impact of anthropogenic and biogenic sources on the seasonal variation in the molecular composition of urban organic aerosols: a field and laboratory study using ultra-high-resolution mass spectrometry. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-5973-2019</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">C9ETPYNF</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ye, Qing; Wang, Mingyi; Hofbauer, Victoria; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Chen, Dexian; Schervish, Meredith; Vogel, Alexander; Mauldin, Roy L.; Baalbaki, Rima; Brilke, Sophia; Dada, Lubna; Dias, António; Duplissy, Jonathan; El Haddad, Imad; Finkenzeller, Henning; Fischer, Lukas; He, Xucheng; Kim, Changhyuk; Kürten, Andreas; Lamkaddam, Houssni; Lee, Chuan Ping; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Leiminger, Markus; Manninen, Hanna E.; Marten, Ruby; Mentler, Bernhard; Partoll, Eva; Petäjä, Tuukka; Rissanen, Matti; Schobesberger, Siegfried; Schuchmann, Simone; Simon, Mario; Tham, Yee Jun; Vazquez-Pufleau, Miguel; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wang, Yonghong; Wu, Yusheng; Xiao, Mao; Baltensperger, Urs; Curtius, Joachim; Flagan, Richard; Kirkby, Jasper; Kulmala, Markku; Volkamer, Rainer; Winkler, Paul M.; Worsnop, Douglas; Donahue, Neil M. (2019) Molecular Composition and Volatility of Nucleated Particles from \textgreeka-Pinene Oxidation between -50 °C and +25 °C. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 53</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b03265</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TX9KI9U5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vogel, Alexander L.; Lauer, Anja; Fang, Ling; Arturi, Katarzyna; Bachmeier, Franziska; Daellenbach, Kaspar R.; Käser, Timon; Vlachou, Athanasia; Pospisilova, Veronika; Baltensperger, Urs; Haddad, Imad El; Schwikowski, Margit; Bjelić, Saša (2019) A Comprehensive Nontarget Analysis for the Molecular Reconstruction of Organic Aerosol Composition from Glacier Ice Cores. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 53</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b03091</link>
      <category>2019</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">NVUJ5Y8Z</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frege, Carla; Ortega, Ismael K.; Rissanen, Matti P.; Praplan, Arnaud P.; Steiner, Gerhard; Heinritzi, Martin; Ahonen, Lauri; Amorim, Antonio; Bernhammer, Anne-Kathrin; Bianchi, Federico; Brilke, Sophia; Breitenlechner, Martin; Dada, Lubna; Dias, Antonio; Duplissy, Jonathan; Ehrhart, Sebastian; El-Haddad, Imad; Fischer, Lukas; Fuchs, Claudia; Garmash, Olga; Gonin, Marc; Hansel, Armin; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Jokinen, Tuija; Junninen, Heikki; Kirkby, Jasper; Kuerten, Andreas; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Leiminger, Markus; Mauldin, Roy Lee; Molteni, Ugo; Nichman, Leonid; Petaja, Tuukka; Sarnela, Nina; Schobesberger, Siegfried; Simon, Mario; Sipila, Mikko; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Tome, Antonio; Vogel, Alexander L.; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wagner, Robert; Xiao, Mao; Yan, Chao; Ye, Penglin; Curtius, Joachim; Donahue, Neil M.; Flagan, Richard C.; Kulmala, Markku; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Winkler, Paul M.; Dommen, Josef; Baltensperger, Urs (2018) Influence of temperature on the molecular composition of ions and charged clusters during pure biogenic nucleation. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 18</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-65-2018</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4VGW9IWC</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Yan, Chao; Dada, Lubna; Bianchi, Federico; Xiao, Mao; Wagner, Robert; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Ahonen, Lauri R.; Amorim, Antonio; Baccarini, Andrea; Bauer, Paulus S.; Baumgartner, Bernhard; Bergen, Anton; Bernhammer, Anne-Kathrin; Breitenlechner, Martin; Brilke, Sophia; Buchholz, Angela; Mazon, Stephany Buenrostro; Chen, Dexian; Chen, Xuemeng; Dias, Antonio; Dommen, Josef; Draper, Danielle C.; Duplissy, Jonathan; Ehn, Mikael; Finkenzeller, Henning; Fischer, Lukas; Frege, Carla; Fuchs, Claudia; Garmash, Olga; Gordon, Hamish; Hakala, Jani; He, Xucheng; Heikkinen, Liine; Heinritzi, Martin; Helm, Johanna C.; Hofbauer, Victoria; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Jokinen, Tuija; Kangasluoma, Juha; Kerminen, Veli-Matti; Kim, Changhyuk; Kirkby, Jasper; Kontkanen, Jenni; Kürten, Andreas; Lawler, Michael J.; Mai, Huajun; Mathot, Serge; Mauldin, Roy L.; Molteni, Ugo; Nichman, Leonid; Nie, Wei; Nieminen, Tuomo; Ojdanic, Andrea; Onnela, Antti; Passananti, Monica; Petäjä, Tuukka; Piel, Felix; Pospisilova, Veronika; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Rissanen, Matti P.; Rose, Clémence; Sarnela, Nina; Schallhart, Simon; Schuchmann, Simone; Sengupta, Kamalika; Simon, Mario; Sipilä, Mikko; Tauber, Christian; Tomé, António; Tröstl, Jasmin; Väisänen, Olli; Vogel, Alexander L.; Volkamer, Rainer; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wang, Mingyi; Weitz, Lena; Wimmer, Daniela; Ye, Penglin; Ylisirniö, Arttu; Zha, Qiaozhi; Carslaw, Kenneth S.; Curtius, Joachim; Donahue, Neil M.; Flagan, Richard C.; Hansel, Armin; Riipinen, Ilona; Virtanen, Annele; Winkler, Paul M.; Baltensperger, Urs; Kulmala, Markku; Worsnop, Douglas R. (2018) Multicomponent new particle formation from sulfuric acid, ammonia, and biogenic vapors. Science advances. 4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aau5363</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">IKGEQ3F5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stolzenburg, Dominik; Fischer, Lukas; Vogel, Alexander L.; Heinritzi, Martin; Schervish, Meredith; Simon, Mario; Wagner, Andrea C.; Dada, Lubna; Ahonen, Lauri R.; Amorim, Antonio; Baccarini, Andrea; Bauer, Paulus S.; Baumgartner, Bernhard; Bergen, Anton; Bianchi, Federico; Breitenlechner, Martin; Brilke, Sophia; Buenrostro Mazon, Stephany; Chen, Dexian; Dias, António; Draper, Danielle C.; Duplissy, Jonathan; El Haddad, Imad; Finkenzeller, Henning; Frege, Carla; Fuchs, Claudia; Garmash, Olga; Gordon, Hamish; He, Xucheng; Helm, Johanna; Hofbauer, Victoria; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Kim, Changhyuk; Kirkby, Jasper; Kontkanen, Jenni; Kürten, Andreas; Lampilahti, Janne; Lawler, Michael; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Leiminger, Markus; Mai, Huajun; Mathot, Serge; Mentler, Bernhard; Molteni, Ugo; Nie, Wei; Nieminen, Tuomo; Nowak, John B.; Ojdanic, Andrea; Onnela, Antti; Passananti, Monica; Petäjä, Tuukka; Quéléver, Lauriane L. J.; Rissanen, Matti P.; Sarnela, Nina; Schallhart, Simon; Tauber, Christian; Tomé, António; Wagner, Robert; Wang, Mingyi; Weitz, Lena; Wimmer, Daniela; Xiao, Mao; Yan, Chao; Ye, Penglin; Zha, Qiaozhi; Baltensperger, Urs; Curtius, Joachim; Dommen, Josef; Flagan, Richard C.; Kulmala, Markku; Smith, James N.; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Hansel, Armin; Donahue, Neil M.; Winkler, Paul M. (2018) Rapid growth of organic aerosol nanoparticles over a wide tropospheric temperature range. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 115</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1807604115</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EUQWZNZK</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zuth, Christoph; Vogel, Alexander L.; Ockenfeld, Sara; Huesmann, Regina; Hoffmann, Thorsten (2018) Ultrahigh-Resolution Mass Spectrometry in Real Time: Atmospheric Pressure Chemical Ionization Orbitrap Mass Spectrometry of Atmospheric Organic Aerosol. Analytical chemistry. 90</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.8b00671</link>
      <category>2018</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">EHXITUBC</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dias, Antonio; Ehrhart, Sebastian; Vogel, Alexander; Williamson, Christina; Almeida, Joao; Kirkby, Jasper; Mathot, Serge; Mumford, Samuel; Onnela, Antti (2017) Temperature uniformity in the CERN CLOUD chamber. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques. 10</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-10-5075-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TDZKMFPC</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wagner, Robert; Yan, Chao; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Duplissy, Jonathan; Nieminen, Tuomo; Kangasluoma, Juha; Ahonen, Lauri R.; Dada, Lubna; Kontkanen, Jenni; Manninen, Hanna E.; Dias, Antonio; Amorim, Antonio; Bauer, Paulus S.; Bergen, Anton; Bernhammer, Anne-Kathrin; Bianchi, Federico; Brilke, Sophia; Mazon, Stephany Buenrostro; Chen, Xuemeng; Draper, Danielle C.; Fischer, Lukas; Frege, Carla; Fuchs, Claudia; Garmash, Olga; Gordon, Hamish; Hakala, Jani; Heikkinen, Liine; Heinritzi, Martin; Hofbauer, Victoria; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Kirkby, Jasper; Kurten, Andreas; Kvashnin, Alexander N.; Laurila, Tiia; Lawler, Michael J.; Mai, Huajun; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Mauldin, Roy L., III; Molteni, Ugo; Nichman, Leonid; Nie, Wei; Ojdanic, Andrea; Onnela, Antti; Piel, Felix; Quelever, Lauriane L. J.; Rissanen, Matti P.; Sarnela, Nina; Schallhart, Simon; Sengupta, Kamalika; Simon, Mario; Stolzenburg, Dominik; Stozhkov, Yuri; Trostl, Jasmin; Viisanen, Yrjo; Vogel, Alexander L.; Wagner, Andrea C.; Xiao, Mao; Ye, Penglin; Baltensperger, Urs; Curtius, Joachim; Donahue, Neil M.; Flagan, Richard C.; Gallagher, Martin; Hansel, Armin; Smith, James N.; Tome, Antonio; Winkler, Paul M.; Worsnop, Douglas; Ehn, Mikael; Sipila, Mikko; Kerminen, Veli-Matti; Petaja, Tuukka; Kulmala, Markku (2017) The role of ions in new particle formation in the CLOUD chamber. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-17-15181-2017</link>
      <category>2017</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BRI5LW3Z</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirkby, Jasper; Duplissy, Jonathan; Sengupta, Kamalika; Frege, Carla; Gordon, Hamish; Williamson, Christina; Heinritzi, Martin; Simon, Mario; Yan, Chao; Almeida, Joao; Troestl, Jasmin; Nieminen, Tuomo; Ortega, Ismael K.; Wagner, Robert; Adamov, Alexey; Amorim, Antonio; Bernhammer, Anne-Kathrin; Bianchi, Federico; Breitenlechner, Martin; Brilke, Sophia; Chen, Xuemeng; Craven, Jill; Dias, Antonio; Ehrhart, Sebastian; Flagan, Richard C.; Franchin, Alessandro; Fuchs, Claudia; Guida, Roberto; Hakala, Jani; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Jokinen, Tuija; Junninen, Heikki; Kangasluoma, Juha; Kim, Jaeseok; Krapf, Manuel; Kuerten, Andreas; Laaksonen, Ari; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Mathot, Serge; Molteni, Ugo; Onnela, Antti; Peraekylae, Otso; Piel, Felix; Petaejae, Tuukka; Praplan, Arnaud P.; Pringle, Kirsty; Rap, Alexandru; Richards, Nigel A. D.; Riipinen, Ilona; Rissanen, Matti P.; Rondo, Linda; Sarnela, Nina; Schobesberger, Siegfried; Scott, Catherine E.; Seinfeld, John H.; Sipilae, Mikko; Steiner, Gerhard; Stozhkov, Yuri; Stratmann, Frank; Tome, Antonio; Virtanen, Annele; Vogel, Alexander L.; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wagner, Paul E.; Weingartner, Ernest; Wimmer, Daniela; Winkler, Paul M.; Ye, Penglin; Zhang, Xuan; Hansel, Armin; Dommen, Josef; Donahue, Neil M.; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Baltensperger, Urs; Kulmala, Markku; Carslaw, Kenneth S.; Curtius, Joachim (2016) Ion-induced nucleation of pure biogenic particles. Nature. 533</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/nature17953</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">P2THLPGI</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gordon, Hamish; Sengupta, Kamalika; Rap, Alexandru; Duplissy, Jonathan; Frege, Carla; Williamson, Christina; Heinritzi, Martin; Simon, Mario; Yan, Chao; Almeida, Joao; Trostl, Jasmin; Nieminen, Tuomo; Ortega, Ismael K.; Wagner, Robert; Dunne, Eimear M.; Adamov, Alexey; Amorim, Antonio; Bernhammer, Anne-Kathrin; Bianchi, Federico; Breitenlechner, Martin; Brilke, Sophia; Chen, Xuemeng; Craven, Jill S.; Dias, Antonio; Ehrhart, Sebastian; Fischer, Lukas; Flagan, Richard C.; Franchin, Alessandro; Fuchs, Claudia; Guida, Roberto; Hakala, Jani; Hoyle, Christopher R.; Jokinen, Tuija; Junninen, Heikki; Kangasluoma, Juha; Kim, Jaeseok; Kirkby, Jasper; Krapf, Manuel; Kuerten, Andreas; Laaksonen, Ari; Lehtipalo, Katrianne; Makhmutov, Vladimir; Mathot, Serge; Molteni, Ugo; Monks, Sarah A.; Onnela, Antti; Perakyla, Otso; Piel, Felix; Petaja, Tuukka; Praplan, Arnaud P.; Pringle, Kirsty J.; Richards, Nigel A. D.; Rissanen, Matti P.; Rondo, Linda; Sarnela, Nina; Schobesberger, Siegfried; Scott, Catherine E.; Seinfeldo, John H.; Sharma, Sangeeta; Sipila, Mikko; Steiner, Gerhard; Stozhkov, Yuri; Stratmann, Frank; Tome, Antonio; Virtanen, Annele; Vogel, Alexander Lucas; Wagner, Andrea C.; Wagner, Paul E.; Weingartner, Ernest; Wimmer, Daniela; Winkler, Paul M.; Ye, Penglin; Zhang, Xuan; Hansel, Armin; Dommen, Josef; Donahue, Neil M.; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Baltensperger, Urs; Kulmala, Markku; Curtius, Joachim; Carslaw, Kenneth S. (2016) Reduced anthropogenic aerosol radiative forcing caused by biogenic new particle formation. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 113</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1602360113</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">QXL9ZEBH</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vogel, Alexander L.; Schneider, Johannes; Mueller-Tautges, Christina; Klimach, Thomas; Hoffmann, Thorsten (2016) Aerosol Chemistry Resolved by Mass Spectrometry: Insights into Particle Growth after Ambient New Particle Formation. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 50</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.6b01673</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">62LP3YHW</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoyle, C. R.; Fuchs, C.; Jaervinen, E.; Saathoff, H.; Dias, A.; El Haddad, I.; Gysel, M.; Coburn, S. C.; Troestl, J.; Bernhammer, A.-K.; Bianchi, F.; Breitenlechner, M.; Corbin, J. C.; Craven, J.; Donahue, N. M.; Duplissy, J.; Ehrhart, S.; Frege, C.; Gordon, H.; Hoeppel, N.; Heinritzi, M.; Kristensen, T. B.; Molteni, U.; Nichman, L.; Pinterich, T.; Prevot, A. S. H.; Simon, M.; Slowik, J. G.; Steiner, G.; Tome, A.; Vogel, A. L.; Volkamer, R.; Wagner, A. C.; Wagner, R.; Wexler, A. S.; Williamson, C.; Winkler, P. M.; Yan, C.; Amorim, A.; Dommen, J.; Curtius, J.; Gallagher, M. W.; Flagan, R. C.; Hansel, A.; Kirkby, J.; Kulmala, M.; Moehler, O.; Stratmann, F.; Worsnop, D. R.; Baltensperger, U. (2016) Aqueous phase oxidation of sulphur dioxide by ozone in cloud droplets. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 16</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-1693-2016</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RSBERPB4</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vogel, Alexander L.; Schneider, Johannes; Mueller-Tautges, Christina; Phillips, Gavin J.; Poehlker, Mira L.; Rose, Diana; Zuth, Christoph; Makkonen, Ulla; Hakola, Hannele; Crowley, John N.; Andreae, Meinrat O.; Poeschl, Ulrich; Hoffmann, Thorsten (2016) Aerosol Chemistry Resolved by Mass Spectrometry: Linking Field Measurements of Cloud Condensation Nuclei Activity to Organic Aerosol Composition. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 50</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.6b01675</link>
      <category>2016</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FD57L7LQ</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yatavelli, Reddy L. N.; Mohr, Claudia; Stark, Harald; Day, Douglas A.; Thompson, Samantha L.; Lopez-Hilfiker, Felipe D.; Campuzano-Jost, Pedro; Palm, Brett B.; Vogel, Alexander L.; Hoffmann, Thorsten; Heikkinen, Liine; Aijala, Mikko; Ng, Nga L.; Kimmel, Joel R.; Canagaratna, Manjula R.; Ehn, Mikael; Junninen, Heikki; Cubison, Michael J.; Petaja, Tuukka; Kulmala, Markku; Jayne, John T.; Worsnop, Douglas R.; Jimenez, Jose L. (2015) Estimating the contribution of organic acids to northern hemispheric continental organic aerosol. Geophysical Research Letters. 42</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/2015GL064650</link>
      <category>2015</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">56FG22KS</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brueggemann, Martin; Vogel, Alexander Lucas; Hoffmann, Thorsten (2014) Analysis of organic aerosols using a micro-orifice volatilization impactor coupled to an atmospheric-pressure chemical ionization mass spectrometer. European Journal of Mass Spectrometry. 20</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1255/ejms.1260</link>
      <category>2014</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">H24EHZ2Y</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigan, A. L.; Russell, L. M.; Takahama, S.; Aijala, M.; Ehn, M.; Junninen, H.; Rinne, J.; Petaja, T.; Kulmala, M.; Vogel, A. L.; Hoffmann, T.; Ebben, C. J.; Geiger, F. M.; Chhabra, P.; Seinfeld, J. H.; Worsnop, D. R.; Song, W.; Auld, J.; Williams, J. (2013) Biogenic and biomass burning organic aerosol in a boreal forest at Hyytiala, Finland, during HUMPPA-COPEC 2010. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-12233-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">85LP6QYS</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huang, R.-J.; Thorenz, U. R.; Kundel, M.; Venables, D. S.; Ceburnis, D.; Ho, K. F.; Chen, J.; Vogel, A. L.; Kuepper, F. C.; Smyth, P. P. A.; Nitschke, U.; Stengel, D. B.; Berresheim, H.; O'Dowd, C. D.; Hoffmann, T. (2013) The seaweeds Fucus vesiculosus and Ascophyllum nodosum are significant contributors to coastal iodine emissions. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-5255-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ADNHVR7Q</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vogel, A. L.; Aijala, M.; Corrigan, A. L.; Junninen, H.; Ehn, M.; Petaja, T.; Worsnop, D. R.; Kulmala, M.; Russell, L. M.; Williams, J.; Hoffmann, T. (2013) In situ submicron organic aerosol characterization at a boreal forest research station during HUMPPA-COPEC 2010 using soft and hard ionization mass spectrometry. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 13</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-10933-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">S56HI8RL</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vogel, A. L.; Aijala, M.; Brueggemann, M.; Ehn, M.; Junninen, H.; Petaja, T.; Worsnop, D. R.; Kulmala, M.; Williams, J.; Hoffmann, T. (2013) Online atmospheric pressure chemical ionization ion trap mass spectrometry (APCI-IT-MSn) for measuring organic acids in concentrated bulk aerosol - a laboratory and field study. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques. 6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-6-431-2013</link>
      <category>2013</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9TLUNJ8A</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noelscher, A. C.; Williams, J.; Sinha, V.; Custer, T.; Song, W.; Johnson, A. M.; Axinte, R.; Bozem, H.; Fischer, H.; Pouvesle, N.; Phillips, G.; Crowley, J. N.; Rantala, P.; Rinne, J.; Kulmala, M.; Gonzales, D.; Valverde-Canossa, J.; Vogel, A.; Hoffmann, T.; Ouwersloot, H. G.; de Arellano, J. Vila-Guerau; Lelieveld, J. (2012) Summertime total OH reactivity measurements from boreal forest during HUMPPA-COPEC 2010. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 12</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-12-8257-2012</link>
      <category>2012</category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ZIAA7QY2</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 08:13:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>